倒数十五秒
T-minus 15 seconds.
改为内部导引
Guidance is internal.
十二、十一、十、九…
Twelve, 11, 10, nine...
开始准备点火
Ignition sequence starts.
六、五、四
Six, five, four,
三、二、一
three, two, one...
零，启动所有引擎
Zero. All engines running.
阿波罗11号升空
Liftoff. We have liftoff on Apollo 11.
燃料和氧气状态稳定
Fuel and oxygen steady.
驾驶舱正常，动力正常
Cabin holding. Power is good.
目前高度是四哩
Altitude, four miles now.
速度是每秒2195尺
Velocity, 2, 195 feet per second.
雷达资料正常
Good radar data.
现在高度3万5千英尺
Altitude now, 33,500 feet.
所有系统正常？
How are you looking? All your systems go?
他们开始行动了抓紧了
They're a go. Hang tight.
可以继续减少动力了
You're a go to continue power descent.
休斯顿，遇到一点乱流
Uh, Houston, I'm getting a little fluctuation.
休斯顿，老鹰号资料传输失误
And, Eagle, Houston, we got data drop-outs.
距离地面3尺，2.5
Three feet down, two and a half.
扬起一些尘土
Picking up some dust.
好，引擎停止
Okay. Engine stop.
老鹰号已登陆
The Eagle has landed.
（2011年1月12日）
（卫星修复任务）
要把我从你身边拉走需要很长时间
It's gonna take a lot to drag me away from you
一百个人或更多的人都无法做到
There's nothing that a hundred men or more could ever do
我祈愿非洲下雨
I bless the rains down in Africa
会花一些时间去做我们从未做过的事情…
Gonna take some time to do the things we never had...
“想念非洲下雨”到底是什么意思？
What does it even mean to "miss the rains down in Africa "?
歌词是：
The lyrics are
“我祈愿非洲下雨”
"I bless the rains down in Africa."
什么？
What?
才不是
No, they're not.
就是啦
Uh, yes, they are.
那就更不合理了
It makes even less sense.
问我就对了
Well, I should know,
因为我在婚礼上唱了这首歌
because I karaoke'd it at my wedding.
我一定是没听到
Well, I must have missed that.
我太专心了，叱吒舞池
I was in the zone. Tearing it up on the dance floor.
你根本不会跳舞
You can't dance to save your life.
有人说过你们斗嘴像老夫老妻吗？
Anyone ever tell you guys you bicker like an old married couple?
因为她就是我工作上的老婆
That's 'cause she's my work wife.
继续工作吧，菜鸟
Back to work, rookie.
…也做不到
...could ever do
我想念非洲下雨
I miss the rain down in Africa
谢谢你牺牲蜜月假和我们上太空
I would like to thank you for spending your honeymoon in space with us.
不是上太空就是去意大利
It was either space or Italy.
但意大利比不上这里的景致
But Italy doesn't beat this view.
我想念非洲下雨
I miss the rains down in Africa
布莱恩，我的老天
Brian. Oh, my God.
我想念非洲下雨
I miss the rains down in Africa
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
布莱恩！
Brian!
马可斯！
Marcus!
救我！我快没空气了
Help me. I 'm losing air.
我快没空气了
I 'm losing air.
布莱恩！
Brian!
乔？福勒，听到请回答
Jo. Fowler, come in.
- 救我！ - 马可斯！
- Help me. - Marcus!
天啊
Oh, God.
好，等我
Okay, hang on.
马可斯？
Marcus.
马可斯，听到请回答
Marcus, come in.
马可斯？
Marcus.
马可斯！他妈的！
Marcus. God damn it.
快啊
Come on.
不！马可斯…
No. Marcus...
不！
No.
我会带你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
月 球 陨 落
（售出）
观众们可能记得那次事故
Our viewers might remember the accident...
即18个月前在例行修复卫星任务中发生的意外
that happened during a routine satellite repair mission 18 months ago.
今天，华盛顿市的上诉法庭作出最终判决
Today, a D.C. court of appeals handed down the final judgement...
针对前宇航员布莱恩·哈珀控诉NASA非法解雇的案子
on ex-astronaut Brian Harper's wrongful termination suit against NASA,
即他的前雇主
his former employer.
我们已取得NASA内部汇报的画面
We have obtained footage of an internal NASA debriefing...
哈珀宣称那次意外
where Harper claimed that the accident
是神秘的科技太空异象所致
was caused by a mysterious technological space anomaly.
你说有个“巨群”冲撞太空船？
So, this so-called "swarm" hit the shuttle?
对
Yes,
我讲第五十遍了
for the 50th time.
它冲进月球的危海
It impacted in the Mare Crisium.
福勒指挥官…
Commander Fowler,
陨石经过或太阳闪焰
a passing meteor or a solar flare
都可能造成这种干扰，对吧？
could have caused that kind of disturbance, correct?
你也知道我当时昏过去了
As you know, I was unconscious,
- 但是… - 是或不是？
- but... - Yes or no?
太阳闪焰会不会导致
Can a solar flare cause
你在太空船系统上看到的干扰？
the kind of disturbance you witnessed in the shuttle's onboard system?
大概会吧
I guess, yes,
技术上是有可能
technically. It could have.
你是在开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
我的朋友命丧太空
I lost my friend up there.
因为你的疏失
Because of negligence.
哈珀曾因降落奋进号而被视为英雄
Harper was once celebrated for his heroic landing of the Endeavour space shuttle
他不顾机上设备完全停摆
in spite of a complete meltdown of all onboard electronics.
哈珀已经没有其他的法律途径
Harper's legal options have been exhausted
那次意外显然是人为疏失所导致
and it's become clear that the accident was the result of human error.
今天的败诉让他彻底跌落神坛
Today's loss is the final blow in this very public fall from grace.
嗨，桑尼
Hey, Sonny.
你非得重看一遍不可吗？
Do you need to be watching that again?
你知道吗？
You know what?
外婆一定迫不及待想见到你
Grandma is going to be so excited to see you.
爸爸不来了，对吧？
Dad's not coming, is he?
你爸还有很多事要忙
Your dad's got a lot going on right now.
我知道，所以我们才会卖了房子
I know. That's why we lost the house.
说不定他感恩节会来看你
Maybe he'll come visit you for Thanksgiving.
好不好？
Would you like that?
我不想搬家
I don't wanna move.
我讨厌纽泽西州
I hate New Jersey.
（十年后）
（加州大学尔湾分校）
（物理与天文学系）
抱歉了
I'm sorry, sir.
（尤金·艾洛伍教授）
我妈常说“事先征得许可不如事后请求原谅”
My mum always said "it's better to beg for forgiveness than ask permission."
（加大尔湾分校，使用者登入）
惨了，是红色还是蓝色？
Oh, crap. Was that red or blue?
拜托你告诉我是蓝色
Please tell me it was blue.
智利国家天文台
Observatorio Nacional de Chile.
- 艾斯特班？ - 哪位？
- Esteban? - Si?
我是艾洛伍教授
It's Professor Arrowood.
看到你登入我们的望远镜了，教授
I see you're logging in to our telescope, Professor.
对，我还在追踪月球的轨道
Oh, yeah. I'm still tracking our Moon's orbit.
可以请你把昨晚的扫描寄给我吗？
Would you mind sending last night's scans?
用我给你的另一个电子信箱，不要用学校的
Use the other e-mail I gave you though, not the school one.
还是老样子
Like always, sir.
扫帚又被人拿走了
先这样吧
Gotta run.
- 再见 - 再见
- Ciao. - Adios.
你们好
Hola senoras.
（安琪儿餐馆）
你迟到了七分半钟
You're seven and a half minutes late.
我要申诉你
I have to write this up.
- 你好  - 嗨
- Hello, there. - Hi.
需要什么？
What can I get you?
我要一份特餐
I'd like a Pastrami Madness...
另外我想请问你
and I would also like to ask you, dear,
特餐是搭配什么酱？
what sauces do you serve with the pastrami?
好，我们有烤肉酱
Oh, yeah. We've got barbecue,
蜂蜜芥末酱
honey mustard,
田园沙拉酱…
ranch...
（轨道距离）
搞什么？
What the fuck!
最后一种是什么？
What was the... The last one?
一份特餐马上好
One Madness coming up.
工作时严禁使用手机
We have a strict no phone policy.
可以休息十分钟吗？
Can I take my 10?
喂？
Hello.
我是KC·豪斯曼博士
My name is Dr. KC Houseman,
我有可能找到人类史上最重要的发现
and I've uncovered what might be the most important discovery in human history.
请你马上转接NASA局长
I need you to patch me through to the director of NASA immediately.
（航空航天局）
亲爱的，我是卖T恤和玩具的
Honey, I sell T-shirts and toys.
我可以帮你转接客服部
I can patch you through to customer service.
请稍等
Please hold.
喂？
Hello?
黑咖啡，两块糖
Black, two sugar.
你会读心啊，谢谢
Oh, you read my mind. Thank you.
你怎么这么早起床？
What are you doing up so early?
我也想问你同一个问题
I could ask you the same.
一切都好吗？
Is everything okay?
会好的
Will be.
我会回来吃晚饭
So I'm gonna be home by dinner.
如果我没回来
If I'm not,
记得叫吉米写作业、洗澡…
make sure Jimmy does his homework, has a bath...
你担心太多了
You worry too much.
有我在一切搞定
I've got everything under control.
好
Right.
再聊
Talk soon.
（约翰逊航天中心）
（德克萨斯州 休斯顿）
好，不要这么多人同时说话
Okay, don't everybody speak at once.
月球轨道改变了
The Moon's orbit has shifted.
什么？
I'm sorry?
轨道半径正在缩减中
Its orbital radius is decreasing.
这不可能
Well, that's not possible.
我们也是这么想
We thought the same,
所以检查了数字又再三确认资料
so we ran the numbers and triple-checked our data.
月球绕着地球转了几十亿年
So, the Moon's been orbiting around the Earth for billions of years,
现在你跟我说它改变轨道？
and now you're telling me it's changed its course?
这又不是幼儿园，说吧
This isn't kindergarten, speak.
对啦，在最近的绕行轨道上
Right, uh, yes. So, on its last orbit,
月球探测器侦测到异常的东西
our Lunar Reconnaissance Probe picked up something strange.
是什么？
What is that?
目前不知道
We don't know.
我们已对它内部散发的气体光谱进行光度测定
We have photometric measurements of gaseous spectra being emitted from inside.
这是哪里？
Where is this?
危海
Mare Crisium.
要我告诉你多少遍？
How many times do I have to tell you?
我有事要马上告诉福勒副局长
I need to speak to Deputy Director Fowler immediately.
但这很紧急
But this is urgent.
我知道限制令是怎么规定的
I understand how a restraining order works,
但如果你们NASA不听我说
but if you people at NASA won't listen to me,
我要怎么…
how am I supposed to...
喂？
Hello?
（SpaceX太空探索技术公司）
埃隆会怎么做？
What would Elon do?
毛德林啊
Oh, Fuzz Aldrin.
我讲过多少次要尿在砂盆里？
How many times have I told you to use the litter box?
真是的
Oh, God.
“宇航员节”
"Astronaut Day."
就是今天
This is today.
毛毛
Fuzz,
你真是天才！
you're a damn genius!
晚点给你抓背奖励
Extra back scratches later.
我们老师说你是爽约的废物
Our teacher said you're a washed up no-show.
她去找人投诉
She's complaining to someone.
你看起来真的不像宇航员
You really don't look like an astronaut.
你是来教我们太空的事吗？
Well, are you going to teach us about space or what?
布莱恩！
Brian!
开门！你三个月没缴房租了！
Open the goddamn door. You're three months late!
靠！
Shit.
我听得见你在里面
I can hear you in there.
- 靠！ - 布莱恩！
- Oh, shit. - Brian!
说白了，月球是个巨型结构
To put it bluntly, the Moon is a megastructure.
你们懂吗？
Do you get it?
大型人造结构
Huge and artificial!
这个不可思议结构的制造者一定觉得我们是可悲的物种
Whoever built this incredible thing must think we're a pathetic species.
但千万别让我讲起日蚀
But don't even get me started on eclipses.
日蚀之所以发生是因为
They're only possible because
月球比太阳小了四百倍
the Moon is exactly 400 times smaller than the Sun,
又更靠近地球四百倍
and exactly 400 times closer to the Earth.
有人知道为什么吗？
Anyone know how that happened?
因为月球是巨型结构？
'Cause the Moon's a megastructure?
对，有人在专心听
Yeah, someone's paying attention!
我告诉你们一件事
Let me tell you kids something.
阿波罗12号的空油箱落地时
When Apollo 12 dropped their empty fuel tank,
撞击让月球发出像钟的声音
the impact made the Moon ring like a bell.
响了好几个小时
It rang for hours.
你们知道为什么吗？
And do you know why?
因为月球是空心的
Because the damn Moon is hollow.
试着接受吧
Put that in your pipe and smoke it.
嗨
Hello.
我是布莱恩·哈珀
I'm Brian Harper.
我今天受邀来演讲
I'm supposed to be speaking here today.
我是巨型结构学家KC·豪斯曼
I'm Dr. KC Houseman, megastructurist.
幸会
It's a real honor.
抱歉，你是谁？
I'm sorry, who are you?
我有个惊天动地的大发现
I've made a shocking discovery.
需要你马上帮我联络NASA
I need you to get me in touch with NASA immediately.
我和NASA目前没再往来了
Well, NASA and I aren't really on speaking terms these days.
你们会的
Well, that will change
等你告诉他们月球脱离轨道之后
when you tell them that the Moon is out of orbit.
真的假的？
Really?
小朋友们，我先去解决这件事
Hey, kids, I'm gonna go get this all sorted out.
马上回来
Be right back.
你看这份资料
Look at the data.
天体不会一夜之间离开运行轨道
A natural body does not change its orbit overnight.
对啦，我的身体正在离开你
Yeah, well, my natural body is walking away from you right now.
月球的动力来源一定出问题了
There must be something wrong with the Moon's power source.
对，一定是这样
Yeah, that must be it.
我就知道你会相信我
I knew you'd believe me.
一般人都当我是个神经病
People usually think I'm some kind of crackpot.
两位，我要送这个冒充我
Hey, fellas, I need this guy escorted off the premises
骚扰一群学童的人离开这里
for impersonating me and creeping out a bunch of school kids.
我没有冒充你
I was not impersonating you.
先生，请你跟我们走
Sir, I'm going to have to ask you to come with us.
抱歉，我已经够忙了
Sorry, man. I got enough on my plate without
没空理说月球脱离轨道的神经病
some crazy guy thinking the Moon's out of orbit.
- 我不是神经病  -好吧
- I'm not crazy! - Okay.
你自己看
Read this.
好啦，我走
All right, I'm on my way.
（强制迁离通知）
（布兰达）
你是不是拨错号码？
Is this a butt dial?
赶快看第16频道
Put on channel 16.
我还以为我们在冷战
Well, I thought we weren 't speaking anymore.
你有在看吗？
Are you watching?
至少闯了两个红灯的两名嫌犯…
The two suspects who have rolled through at least two red lights...
好吧
Okay,
有个白痴以为能甩掉警察
looks like some idiot tried to outrun the cops.
对，那个白痴是你儿子
Yeah. That idiot is your son.
桑尼又没有车，那辆野马我还在修
Sonny doesn't even have a car. I'm still fixing up the Mustang.
汤姆送他一辆车当生日礼物
Tom gave him one for his birthday.
车子停下来了，是一部昂贵的跑车
The car has stopped. It's an expensive sports car.
两名20出头的年轻人…
Two young men that appear to be in their 20s...
你有在看吗？
Are you seeing this?
洛杉矶警方拘留了他们
LAPD have them in custody.
两人出来兜风，结果要睡在警局了
Out for a joy ride and this day is not going to end well for them.
好了，又是一场飞车追逐…
There you have it. Another high-speed car chase...
下一个案子是桑尼·哈珀
Next case, Sonny Neil Harper.
这上面说你刚满18岁
It says here you just turned 18.
很遗憾，法律认定你是成年人了
Unfortunately, that makes you an adult in the eyes of the law.
什么？
What?
你不说句话吗？
Aren't you gonna say something?
因为你的行为莽撞
Because of the reckless nature of your actions
被捕时身上持有的毒品量…
and the amount of illegal substances present at the time of your arrest...
不，庭上，那些毒品不是他的，是他朋友的
No, Your Honor. Those drugs weren't his. They were just his buddy's.
- 他们要去演唱会  - 法庭上安静
- They were on their way to a concert. - Quiet in my court.
他只是害怕，所以才会逃跑
Well, he just got scared. That's why he took off.
好，够了，法警！
All right, that's it. Bailiff.
庭上，请原谅我委托人父亲的言行
Your Honor, excuse the actions of my client's father.
不管保释金多少，我们马上付钱
We're prepared to pay whatever the ball is right now.
钱不是问题
Money's no object.
那被告就有逃亡之虞了
Well, I guess that makes the defendant a flight risk.
庭上，我们绝对无意冒犯
Your Honor, we do not mean to offend the court in any way.
这场保释听证会延到下周
I'm postponing this bail hearing till next week.
法警，把哈珀先生带走
Bailiff, remove Mr. Harper.
等一下，你不能…不要听他的
Wait. You can't... Don't listen to him.
不能把他关一个星期，我求求你
You can't put him in jail for a week. Please, I'm begging you.
桑尼，我会保你出来的
Sonny, I'm gonna get you out.
如果你要最划算的服务
If you're looking for the deal of your life,
就来雷克萨斯汽车找汤姆·罗培兹
come to Tom Lopez Lexus,
在这里你不只是个顾客
where you're not just a customer,
我们待你如同家人
we treat you like family.
你知道法庭是怎么运作的吗？
Do you have any idea how a courtroom operates?
你的律师什么也没做
Your lawyer was doing nothing.
原来你懂得比我的律师更多
Oh, so you know better than my lawyer
他的律师费是五万美元耶！
who's on a $50,000 retainer!
我以为钱不是问题，汤姆
I thought money was no object, Tom.
不，没钱就有问题了
Oh, no, no, no. It is when you don't have any.
对了，干得好
Nice move, by the way.
桑尼现在有逃亡之虞了
Sonny's now a flight risk.
对啦
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
这家伙真够夸张，不可思议
This guy's unbelievable. Unbelievable.
好了，大家都冷静
All right, everyone, just cool it.
- 到底怎么回事？  - 怎么回事？
- Now, what the hell happened? - Oh, what happened?
布莱恩管不住嘴就说了不该说的话
When Brian had to open his big mouth, he had a little speech.
老天，下地狱吧，汤姆
Oh, my God. Go to hell, Tom.
对，你知道吗？
Yeah, you know what?
你滚到外太空，离我们远点
And you go to outer space, far away from us.
好了
Guys!
我们只是想救出桑尼
We're all just trying to help Sonny right here.
布莱恩想救桑尼？几时的事？
Oh, wait, Brian's trying to help Sonny? Since when?
布兰达，你是看上这蠢货哪一点？
Brenda, honestly, what do you see in this schmuck?
你自以为了不起吗？
Oh, you're a big man, aren't you?
怎么发生的？他为何不在南加大？
How did this happen? Why wasn't he at USC?
你送了他新公寓他就搬出去了
He moved out when you got him that new apartment.
去问他啊
So ask him.
他最近都不回我电话了
He barely returns my calls anymore.
他对我也一样啦
Welcome to the club.
KC，是你吗？
Oh, KC, is that you?
妈，迷迭香
Hey, Mum. Rosmarinus officinalis.
有研究发现闻迷迭香
A few studies have found that smelling rosemary
可以改善短期记忆
can improve your short-term memory.
太好了，谢谢你
Oh, that's lovely, dear. Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不，妈，让我来
Oh, no, no, no, Mum. Let me do that.
好了
There we go.
你感觉怎样？
So, how are you feeling?
好极了
Great.
不要一直讲我的事
But enough about me.
这里的人都知道
Everybody here knows that
我儿子是在NASA工作的天才
my son is a genius working at NASA.
什么？
What?
妈，我是个无名小卒
I'm a nobody, Mum.
我觉得你很了不起
Well, you're somebody to me.
其实我有个发现，但不重要啦
I actually did make a discovery. But it doesn't matter.
没人要听我说
No one will listen to me.
逼他们听啊
Then make them.
逼他们听？
Make them listen?
嗨
Oh, hello.
你是新来的吗？
Are you new here?
不是
No, Mum.
我是KC
It's me. It's KC.
你儿子
Your son.
请问谁能告诉我这是什么？
Can someone tell me what the hell I'm looking at?
月球进入了椭圆轨道
The Moon has entered an elliptical orbit.
意思是？
Meaning?
它会绕着我们转三圈
It'll circle around us three times
然后抵达一万七千公里的洛希极限
before it reaches the Roche Limit at 17,000 kilometers.
届时如城市般大小的月球碎片
At that point, city-sized pieces of Moon debris
就会朝我们飞撒而来
will rain down on us.
所以是三个月后？
So we have three months?
不完全正确
Not exactly.
随着月球愈靠近我们
As the Moon moves closer to us,
一个月的时间就会开始缩短
our months will begin to shorten.
我们估计的时间约为三个星期
We've estimated a timeline of roughly three weeks.
可能还不到
Maybe less than that.
我们刚收到几张新的高清扫描
We have some new high-res scans that just came in.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
坑底是有个洞吗？
Is that a hole in the crater floor?
那我们现在怎么办？
So what are our options here?
我们必须回月球上看看
We have to go back to the Moon.
去看看那里的情况
We have to see what's going on up there.
我们要如何载人？
How do we carry crew?
我已经找欧洲那边谈过了
I've already talked to my contacts in Europe.
STC-62应该明天就能升空
We can potentially get a STC-62 en route by tomorrow.
应该？好极了
Potentially? Great.
我去向总统报告可能发生的事
I'll just brief the president on a maybe.
这件事不准对外声张
In the meantime, everyone keep your mouths shut.
（警讯：月球偏离轨道）
这可能做不到
That might be a problem.
两分钟前消息在推特传开了
It's, uh, trending on Twitter as of two minutes ago.
你前夫找你
It's your ex-husband.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨，道格
Hey, Doug,
我现在有点忙，什么事？
I'm a little busy right now. What is it?
是真的吗？
Is it true?
告诉我这是误传
Tell me there's been some kind of mistake.
我也想啊
I wish I could,
但计算后是对的
but the math actually checks out.
所以是真的
So, it's happening.
吉米还好吗？
How's Jimmy?
你若是偶尔有见到他就会知道了
Well, you'd know if you saw him once in a while.
请你不要跟我吵，我常打给他
Please don't start. I call him all the time.
抱歉，先这样吧
Sorry, I gotta run.
- 庭上  - 我的老天
- Your Honor. - Jesus Christ!
看来挂你电话还不够明确
I guess hanging up wasn't clear enough.
我只耽误你两分钟
I just need two minutes of your time.
给你讲到门口
You have till I reach the door.
我有一台经典摩托车和我儿子的古董野马
I got a classic bike and my son's vintage Mustang
可以抵押，让我筹到你需要的钱
that I can use as collateral till I get money, whatever you need.
你是想贿赂我吗？
Are you trying to bribe me?
在法院里？
In a courthouse?
我只是想救回我儿子
I just wanna get my son back.
法庭关闭了
The courts are closed.
星期一会开吗？
Will they reopen Monday?
不可能
Not likely.
这话是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
我只是想赶在大塞车前离开这里
Look, I'm just trying to get the heck outta here before the traffic becomes a nightmare.
- 建议你也赶快走  - 突发新闻
- I suggest you do the same. - Breaking news.
我们要现场直播NASA的新闻快报
We go now live to the NASA press briefing
讨论月球偏离轨道的记者会
to discuss the Moon being out of orbit.
天文学家最近发现月球表面有亮点
Astronomers have noticed bright lights on the lunar surface lately.
你知道匿名爆料者的身分吗？
Do you know the identity of the anonymous source?
各位
Everyone, please.
我们相信月球探测任务
We 're confident that the lunar recon mission
会提供解决这个问题所需的资料
will provide the necessary data to address the problem.
不必惊慌
There's no need to panic.
先这样
That's all for now.
你刚才对全国撒了谎
You just lied to the whole country.
听我的，你在我底下工作
Get in line, you work for me.
我效力于美国人民，你却欺瞒他们
I work for the American people, and you're keeping them in the dark.
好吧
Yeah.
NASA想要粉饰太平
NASA is completely downplaying this.
想像海边的潮汐
Imagine the tides on the coast...
涨了几百倍高，往内陆移动几百哩
growing hundreds of times larger, moving hundreds of miles inland,
你就知道目前的情况有多危急了
then you'll get an idea of what we 're in for.
持反对意见者认为你在夸大…
Some of your harshest critics claim that you're exaggerating...
所有飞西岸的航班都取消了
All flights to the West Coast have been cancelled.
我还在堵车
And I'm stuck in traffic.
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
往高处移动是唯一可能保命的方法
Moving to higher ground it's the only possible chance of surviving this.
老婆，我们应该去亚斯本
Honey. We should go to Aspen.
那桑尼怎么办？我们不能丢下他
What about Sonny? We can'tjust leave him there.
不，我们不会丢下他
No, no, no. We 're not gonna leave him.
法官定了保释金，律师就会保释他
The lawyer's gonna get him out the moment the judge sets bail.
我再想办法送他去科罗拉多
And I'll find a way to get him to Colorado.
我们要去科罗拉多？
We're going to Colorado?
不，汤姆
No. No, Tom.
较大的地球引力
Earth's stronger gravity...
会完全摧毁月球，并且把成千上万的…
will completely break the Moon apart and send thousands of...
- 直径1000多米的碎片雨点般砸向地球  - 好了，Google
-  mile-sized chunks raining down upon the planet. - Okay. Hey, Google.
关掉电视
Turn off the TV.
- 去打包行李  - 关掉电视
- Girls, go pack. - Turning the TV off.
去打包雪靴，动作快
Girls, go pack your snow boots. Come on. Hurry up.
我们要开始为女儿们做打算
We have to start thinking about the girls.
相信我，我们不会忘了桑尼
And trust me, we are not gonna forget about Sonny.
倒数五秒
T-minus five seconds.
四、三
Four, three,
二、一
two, one.
点火
Ignition.
好了
This is it.
全世界都在屏息以待
The entire world is holding its collective breath
NASA和欧洲各大太空机构的联合行动
as the joint missions between NASA and the European Space Agencies
今天要升空
take to the skies today.
各国都对于航空航天局的探月任务很乐观
Nations remain hopeful of NA SA 's lunar mission
民众持续大量采买和囤积物资
as frantic shoppers continue to stockpile supplies
月球恐慌引发大批人潮移出都会区
as mounting Moon terror fuels the mass migration out of metropolitan areas.
文明社会已经沉沦了
Civilization has already taken a serious nosedive.
打家劫舍在英国各地随处可见
Looting has become a favorite pastime in the United Kingdom.
恐惧和惊慌占据了我们的市区
Fear and panic have overtaken our city.
国民警卫队拼命地想维持秩序
The National Guard struggles to restore some kind of order.
保持清醒吧，我的兄弟姐妹们
Stay awake, my brothers and sisters.
在繁星从天而坠时，要保持清醒
As the stars fall from Heaven, stay awake!
这些武装的宗教狂热份子
These armed religious fanatics
在全国各地累积了数千名信徒
have racked up thousands of followers all over the country.
播报其它新闻
In other news,
知名科学家如今都在探讨
prominent scientists are now exploring the possibility
月球是某种绕行巨型结构的可能性
that perhaps the Moon could be some sort of orbital megastructure.
最早是非主流天文学家常用的名词
A term first popularized by fringe astronomers,
巨型结构是指行星大小的人造物
megastructures describe artificial planet-sized objects
据说藉由控制恒星获得动力
said to be powered by captured stars.
这个曾是偏激的理论如今获得了
This once radical possibility is now gaining traction
急欲找到答案的科学界的广泛关注
among a scientific community desperate for answers.
出来！双手举高！
Come out! Hands up!
别激动
Easy, easy.
你是几天前的那个宇航员
You're that astronaut guy from the other day.
我不小心扔掉了一些很重要的文件
I accidentally threw away some very important papers.
算你走运，清洁员一个礼拜没来了
Lucky for you, sanitation hasn't come by all week.
对，算我走运
Yeah, it's, uh, lucky for me.
（轨道距离）
轨道距离？
"Orbital distance"?
你在找的是这个吗？
Are you looking for this?
（KC豪斯曼博士）
各位巨型结构学家…
My fellow megastructurists,
如果你正在看这段影片
if you're watching this, then you know by now
你应该知道我们麻烦大了
a huge problem is heading our way,
只有我们能解决这个问题
and we're the only ones who can solve it.
紧急召开会议，即刻在老地方见
An emergency meeting is being called, our usual place immediately.
洛杉矶棕榈饭店，今天晚上6点
L.A. Palm Hotel. Today. 18:00.
提供免费贝果
Free bagels.
月球轨道嵌入完成
Lunar orbit insertion complete.
休斯顿，我们正在接近危海
Houston, we 're approaching the Mare Crisium.
开始旋转太空舱
Initiating capsule rotation.
好的
Affirmative.
15度
Fifteen degrees.
30度
Thirty.
45度
Forty-five.
70度
Seventy.
90度
Ninety.
STC-62就定位
STC-62 in position.
休斯顿，看见了吗？
Houston, you seeing this?
是的，看见了
Copy, we see it.
准备部署探测器
Prepare to deploy the probe.
好的
Affirmative.
释放探测器
Releasing probe.
等待第二阶段指令
Stand by for stage two.
稳定落下
Dropping steadily.
（洛杉矶棕榈饭店）
每个平台我都有贴文
Iposted on every platform.
为何NASA那些白痴没看出真正的问题？
Why don't those idiots at NASA see the real problem?
因为他们显然没读过知名宇宙学家卡尔·萨根的著作
Because they obviously haven't read famed cosmologist Carl Sagan's work,
他在书里明确提到
where he clearly states
天然卫星不可能是空心的
that a natural satellite cannot be a hollow object.
这个我讲了很多年，豪斯曼博士
I... I've been saying that for years, Dr. Houseman.
锡吉，现在讲这个也没用吧？
That doesn't help us now, does it, Ziggy?
在座都是世上最聪明又有远见的人
This room is full of the smartest and most visionary people in the world.
我们都知道月球是人造结构
We all know the Moon's a constructed object. Okay?
一定有办法解决
There has to be a way to fix it.
拜托，各位
Come on, people,
跳脱框架思考
think outside the box.
奥斯瓦尔德干的（此人枪杀了肯尼迪）
Oswald did it.
够了，盖瑞，现在别讲这个
Oh, damn it, Gary. Not now.
哈珀先生？
Mr. Harper.
你怎么会在这儿？
What are you doing here?
可能是我犯了个大错
Probably making a huge mistake.
方便谈谈吗？
Can we talk?
你怎么知道我在这儿？
How did you know I was here?
你的网站
Your website.
你看了我的部落格？
You read my blog?
你比任何人更早知道这件事
You knew all this was happening before anyone.
也比NASA更早
Before NASA.
怎么知道的？
How?
这很重要吗？
Why bother?
你又会骂我神经病
You're just gonna say I'm crazy again.
试试看啊
Try me.
多年来我一直在研究遥远的行星
Well, for years I've been studying distant planets,
寻找绕行的巨型结构 但是…
searching for one of these orbiting megastructures. But...
我从没想过在这里就有一个
I never could have imagined there'd be one right here,
就在我们自家后院
in our own backyard.
有没有听过戴森球？
Ever heard of a Dyson sphere?
有
Yeah.
每个巨型结构都会有个坚实的外壳包住的动力核心
Every megastructure has a rigid shell built around a power core.
可能是被控制住汲取能源的白矮星
Most likely a captured white dwarf that's being harnessed for energy.
月球内部的核心显然出了问题
Something obviously happened to the one inside our Moon
所以才会偏离轨道
and that's why it's veering off course.
你果然还是神经病
Yeah, still crazy.
你不打算相信我干嘛还来？
Why did you come here if you're not going to believe me?
因为我知道那种感觉
'Cause I know what it's like
有话想告诉别人却没人要听
to try to tell people something and have no one listen.
探测器深度已达24.5公里
Probe depth has reached 24.5 kilometers.
25公里
Twenty-five kilometers.
停在25.6公里
Holding steady at 25.6 kilometers.
还是停着
Still holding.
- 停止了吗？  - 它回来了
- It stopped? - It's coming back.
24公里
Twenty-four kilometers.
20公里
Twenty.
15公里
Fifteen.
又出问题了
We got another problem.
- 月球轨道再次偏移  - 什么？
- The Moon's orbit is shifting again. - What?
它在自行修正轨道
It's correcting itself.
休斯顿，我们发生了机械故障
Houston, we're experiencing some kind of malfunction.
休斯顿，听到请回答
Houston, do you copy? Houston, do you copy?
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
我不知道
I don't know.
（警告：侦测到机身受损）
机身受损，戴头盔
Hull breach. Helmets.
（无信号）
新闻快报
In breaking news,
NASA刚才修正了
NASA has just corrected...
月球坠落地球路径的最初预测
their initial projection of the Moon's path over Earth.
（月球轨道偏移导致美国洪灾）
政府刚才下令整个西岸大学疏散
The governor has just ordered the mass evacuation of the entire West Coast,
建议民众紧急前往高处避难
recommending that people urgently head to higher ground.
两位！
Guys!
潮水冲过来了
The... The... The tide, it's coming.
快点，我们赶快逃
Come on. We gotta get outta here.
等等！
Wait!
大家上楼！快！
Everybody, upstairs. Go! Everybody, get up!
大家都起来！快点！动作快！
Come on! Go, go!
KC，你在干嘛？
KC, what are you doing?
K·C！
KC!
KC，撑住
KC, hang on!
我不会游泳
I can't swim!
豪斯曼博士！
Dr. Houseman!
抓紧！
Hang on!
他在那儿，他在那儿
He's right there. He's right there.
抓紧！
Hang on!
过来
Come on!
过来！
Come on.
过来
这是某种有自觉
It's some kind of self-aware,
会自我复制的个体
self-replicating singularity.
像机器一样？
Like a machine?
机器没有智慧，这个有
Machines don't have intelligence. This does.
这就是我们害怕的人工智能
It's everything we feared about Al.
它早就知道我们要来了
And it knew we were coming.
可能是被太空舱的电子信号引出来
So it was probably drawn out by the electronic signature of the capsule.
我们自以为了解的宇宙本质都被…
Everything we thought we knew about the nature of the universe has just...
彻底推翻了
gone out the window.
我们还没准备好
We're not prepared for this.
黛比，不要争论了，快打包行李
Deb, don't argue, just pack your stuff.
我们赶快逃命
We're leaving.
你想落跑？
So you're just gonna quit?
不然你要我怎样？
What do you want me to do?
我要你帮忙搞清楚那是什么
I want you to help us figure out what the hell this thing is,
我们好对付它
so we can beat it.
我们没有设备
We're not equipped for that.
你也看到我们面对的是什么了
You've seen what we're up against.
你早就想要我这份工作了，福勒
You've been gunning for my job for a while, Fowler.
恭喜，送你吧
Congrats, it's yours.
你隐瞒了什么？
What are you not telling me?
你有Q级别的安全许可权
You've got Q clearance.
那个洞就在危海
The hole is in the Mare Crisium.
哈珀公听会上讲的就是那个
That's what the Harper hearings were all about.
如果你想深入NASA的机密
If you're serious about going down the NASA rabbit hole,
就去找霍登菲尔德
you should pay a visit to Holdenfield.
这是你的通行许可证
Here's your clearance.
（NASA，阿尔伯特·哈钦斯）
（国家航空航天局 管制区域）
你是怎么进来的？
How did you get down here?
这是哈钦斯给我的
Hutchings gave me this.
我需要STX-136A所有的资料
I'll need all records of STX-136A.
你在等什么吗？
You waiting for something?
（布莱恩·哈珀的头盔影像）
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
那是什么…
I feel it.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
霍登菲尔德？
Holdenfield?
你不应该动那个
You're not supposed to have that,
136阿尔法
136 Alpha.
那是机密
That's classified.
最高机密
Top secret.
NASA为什么要隐瞒这一切？
Why is NASA lying about all this?
1969年7月20日
July 20th, 1969.
“我的一小步”
"One small step for man,
“人类的一大步… 废话一大堆”
"one giant leap for..." Yada, yada, yada.
你在学校学到的是阿波罗11号
In school, you were taught that Apollo 11
和控制中心断了联络
lost contact with Mission Control
长达两分钟
for two minutes.
那是谎言
Not true.
控制中心切断了他们和世界的连线
Mission Control cut their feed to the world
因为他们那天有个重大发现
because they found something on that day.
奇怪的搏动闪光
Strange pulsating lights
从月球外壳底下发射出来
emanating from beneath the Moon's crust.
被指派隐瞒这件事的人是我
It was me who was assigned to keep it under wraps.
阿波罗号人员都配合，大家跟随
The Apollo crew played ball. Everybody after.
只有布莱恩·哈珀不肯
Just Brian Harper wouldn't.
他们说他疯了
They called him crazy.
像垃圾一样丢了他
Threw him out with the trash.
你要告诉我的是月球
You're telling me that the Moon
其实是人类史上最大的骗局？
was effectively the biggest cover-up in human history?
最大？或许吧
Biggest? Probably.
你的双手也染了血
You had blood on your hands, too.
对
Yeah, well,
奉命行事的人…
anyone who follows orders...
都是共犯吧？
pretty much always does, don't they?
那种科技…
That technology,
领先我们好几百万年
it's light years ahead of us.
相较之下…
Compared to that,
我们还在石器时代
we're the Stone Age.
我们阻止它的唯一机会…
The only shot we had to stop it...
就是ZX-7
was Zulu X-Ray 7.
它被尘封了，束之高阁
It was shut down. Shelved.
因为预算问题
For budgetary reasons.
指挥官，还有更要紧的事等着我…
Well, Commander, I have pressing business waiting for me...
在我桌上
on my desk.
我们都快要没时间了
The sand in the hourglass is dropping quickly for all of us.
大势已去了啊
It's as good as gone.
真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
真的
Really.
他妈的
Damn it.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
联络不上我儿子
I can't reach my son.
听说你以前是个宇航员
Word is, um, you're an astronaut,
所以你一定知道
so you must know that
月球内部全是农作物
the entire inside of the Moon is full of produce.
KC，请你告诉这位仁兄
KC, can you tell Birkenstocks here
我快要想把他扔出窗外了
that I'm dangerously close to hurling him out a window?
好，我们找个空房间
Okay, well, let's find an empty room.
不然印加人的马铃薯是哪来的？
How do you think the Incas got their potatoes?
抱歉
Sorry.
你说过只要我们能毁了这玩意儿…
You said that if we can destroy this thing...
我们研究过
We have a theory...
月球应该会回到原始轨道
that the Moon might return to its original orbit.
你提议我们到底要怎么做？
And how do you propose we do that exactly?
你自己也说用现代太空船不可行
You said so yourself, using a modern spacecraft is not feasible.
我正在想办法
I am working on a solution.
谢谢你的努力
We appreciate your effort,
但现在这是军事行动
but this is now a military operation.
接下来由我们接手
We'll take it from here.
道格！等等！
Doug! Wait!
如果你发射核子武器
If you launch nukes,
辐射落尘会害死全世界的人
the global fallout is gonna kill everybody.
有谁提到核武了吗？
Who said anything about nukes?
你这是大错特错了
You are making a big mistake here.
请你让我先拟定计划
Please, let me put together a plan.
我们有个计划了
We have a plan.
你和吉米跟我一起去科罗拉多吧
Look, why don't you and Jimmy come with me to Colorado?
你们在那儿会很安全
You'll be safe there.
你是要我做什么？
What are you asking me to do?
要我放弃吗？
Quit? Give up?
我是要你为我们的儿子着想
I'm asking you to think about our son.
我是在为我们的儿子着想
I am thinking about our son.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
牢里
Uh, jail.
他是个好孩子，只是犯了点错
He's a good kid, just made a mistake.
我以前也是一直做蠢事
I was always doing stupid things.
不知道我爸妈怎么受得了我
Don't know how my parents put up with me.
我们家从来就没什么钱
We never had a lot of money,
但有时候我们会买炸鱼薯条
but sometimes we'd all get fish 'n chips,
坐在码头上看星星好几个小时
sit out on the dock and just watch the stars for hours.
那是我第一次梦想当宇航员
That was when I first dreamed of being an astronaut.
在我爸过世之后
After my father passed,
我妈想搬回美国
my mum wanted to move back to the States.
我说我想当宇航员，我爸还嘲笑我
My dad laughed when I told him I wanted to be an astronaut.
他不相信你？
Didn't believe in you?
这是委婉的说法
Oh, that's putting it lightly.
我拼了命才进入NASA
I worked my ass off to get into NASA.
我看过你上次任务的报导
I read all about your last mission.
你看到外星人的科技
You saw alien tech.
NASA坚持那是个陨石
And NASA insisted it was a meteor.
其实不是吗？
But it wasn't?
我从没见过那种东西
It was unlike anything I'd ever seen.
最糟的是…
And, you know, the worst part
我有个朋友死在太空中
is I lost a friend up there.
而且是我的错
And it was my fault.
拜托，怎么会是你的错？
Oh, come on. How was it your fault?
你救了太空船、救了福勒
You saved the shuttle. You saved Fowler.
换来很棒的回报
A lot of good that did.
离婚、破产，我儿子还恨我
I'm divorced, broke, my son hates me.
天哪，我好嫉妒你
God, I am so jealous.
外星人科技
Alien tech.
超赞的
It's freakin' awesome.
极端天气重创东部和墨西哥湾沿岸
Extreme weather is hammering the Eastern Seaboard and Gulf Coast
潮水高涨泛滥造成居民和财产损失
with high tides and flooding wreaking havoc on residents and properties.
还没前往高处避难的观众
Folks, if you aren't already on high ground,
最好尽快赶往高处
you better get there as soon as possible.
身为一个交换生
Um, as an exchange student,
你确定他们会让我进碉堡吗？
are you sure they're going to let me into the bunker?
确定，放心吧，我会处理
Yeah. Don't worry about it. I'll take care of it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
…以及人口稠密地区的死亡
...and loss of life in populated areas.
从孟加拉传来的画面令人惊心动魄…
As you can see, the images coming out of Bangladesh are simply horrific...
我们会死吗？
Are we gonna die?
不会的，宝贝
No. No, sweetheart.
我知道发生的这一切似乎很可怕
I know all of this that's happening seems so scary,
但我们不会死，懂吗？
but we are not gonna die. Okay?
我们和爸爸去科罗拉多就安全了
We're all gonna be safe with Dad in Colorado.
你还会发射火箭去月球吗？
Are you sending more rockets to the Moon?
没有
No.
没有，你知道为什么吗？因为我们…
No. You know why? Because we don't...
我们没有火箭了
We don't have any more of these.
为什么？
Why not?
因为全都在博物馆了
Because they're all in museums.
而且…
And, um...
我爱你，宝贝
I love you, sweetheart.
嗨，道格
Hey, Doug.
ZX-7是什么？
What is a ZX-7?
是谁告诉你的？
Who told you about that?
告诉我，那是什么？
Well, come on. What is it?
ZX-7是一种电磁脉冲武器
Zulu X-Ray Seven was a prototype EMP device.
但研发小组被解散了
But the program got disbanded.
好吧
Okay, well,
显然月球里面那玩意儿是科技产物
it's clear that this thing inside the Moon is technological in nature, right?
我想他们是认为电磁脉冲武器能解决掉它
I assume they thought an EMP could take the thing out.
我们无法上太空，所以这没有意义
We don't have a way into space so this is a moot point.
好吧，测试到什么阶段了？
Okay, well, how far along was the testing?
乔辛达，NASA没核准新任务
Jocinda, NASA isn't cleared for another mission.
这件事就让我来操心吧
How about you let me worry about that?
卫星定位系统锁定在着陆区
GPS is locked on L2.
补偿纬度往西负4.5度
Compensate latitude by minus 4.5 west.
4.5度，收到
4.5 degrees. Copy.
速度减为10节
Reducing to 10 knots.
开门！
Open the door.
- 哪位？ - 布莱恩·哈珀？
- Yeah? - Brian Harper?
对
Yeah.
请你跟我们走
We need you to come with us.
事关国家安全
It's a matter of national security.
好，等我一下
All right. Give me a second.
我去哪儿都要带着他
I'm not going anywhere without him.
对，我们是个团队
Yeah, we're a team.
对不起，小姐
Sorry, I'm sorry, miss.
抱歉
Sorry.
对不起！
Oh, sorry, sorry.
已经将近三小时了
It's been nearly three hours.
这不可能是个好兆头
That can't be a good sign.
你吃那么多药干嘛？
What's with all the pill popping?
你全身冒汗，还好吗？
You're really sweating over there. You okay?
还好
Yeah.
不好
No.
我多次闯入加州大尔湾分校
I broke into UC Irvine multiple times.
弄丢了他们的两支拖把
I lost two of their mops.
他们可能知道了
They probably know.
开什么玩笑？不会吧
Oh, you gotta be kidding me. No.
我也没比你想在这儿
Look, I don't want to be here any more than you do.
坐吧
Sit down.
不，我不必再听你的命令了
No, no, no. I don't have to take orders from you anymore.
我很好奇，你还在背叛朋友吗？
I'm just curious, you still screwing over your friends?
- 你在跟我说话？真的假的？  - 这里有多少人…
- Oh, you talking about me? Really? - How many of these wonderful people here...
别吵了！
Guys!
这位是谁？
Who the hell is this?
我是KC·豪斯曼博士
Dr. KC Houseman, ma'am.
我写了好几封邮件给你
I wrote you several e-mails,
但你都没回复
but you never responded.
这是怎么回事？
What's this all about?
跟我来
Follow me.
你们即将看到
What you're about to see,
只有极少数人看过的东西
only a handful of people have ever seen before.
KC比你们更早知道月球偏离轨道
KC knew the Moon was out of orbit before you guys did.
我公开研究结果时社交媒体沸腾了
Social media went wild when I posted my research.
- 你就是那个不明爆料者？  - 对
- You're the "unidentified source"? - Oh, yes.
天哪
Oh, God.
莫斯利，调阅坑道的画面
Mosley, pull up the tunnel, please.
我们从指数估计深度超过25公里
Our readings estimate its depth to be over 25 kilometers.
那是危海
That's the Mare Crisium.
没错
Exactly.
我想多年前发生的事
I think whatever happened all those years ago
直接导致了现在发生的事
is directly responsible for what's happening right now.
你现在相信我了？
So you believe me now?
我看了你的头盔影像
I saw your helmet cam.
现在道歉有点迟了
It's a little late for an apology.
我们都被蒙在鼓里
We were both lied to.
上次国际任务不只是出了错
The international mission didn't just go sideways.
而是遭到攻击了
It was attacked.
某种高科技生物
A technological life form.
不会吧
No effin' way.
它攻击时，月球试图回到原始的轨道
During the attack, the Moon was attempting to return to its original orbit,
直到这玩意儿回到月球内部
until this thing went back inside the Moon.
这就是我一直想告诉你们的事
This is what I've been trying to tell you.
它在入侵这个巨型结构的动力核心
It's doing something to the megastructure's power core.
- 什么？巨型结构？  - 请你不要问
- Excuse me. The megastructure? - Please don't ask.
我们的月球很有可能是外星人造的
It's highly likely our Moon was built by aliens.
必须进入内部进行第一次接触
We have to get inside and make first contact.
- 我就叫你不要问了  - 好吧
- I told you not to ask. - All right, look,
我们计划进行攻击这玩意儿的任务
we're planning a mission to attack this thing.
唯一的问题它能感知我们的科技
The only problem is, is it recognizes our technology.
所以我们需要你
Which is why we need you.
没想到我会再听到你说这句话
Well, I never thought I'd hear you say that again.
你是唯一曾经不用动力就降落太空船的飞行员
You're the only pilot to ever land a shuttle without power.
这也不是什么特殊技能
Not exactly a hirable skill.
现在是了
Well, it is right now,
所以我要把你的工作还给你
which is why I'm offering you yourjob back,
并且…
and...
我亲自…
I'm personally...
恳求你的帮忙
asking you for your help.
答应吧，布莱恩
Say yes, Brian.
我不知道
I don't know.
我自己有很多问题要解决
I got a lot of my own problems down here.
月球要撞上地球…
And the Moon falling onto Earth...
不是其中之一吗？
isn't one of them?
找你来是我错了
I was wrong to bring you here.
我说完了
I am done.
你打算要怎么上去？
How do you plan on getting up there?
你也知道我们的太空船都在博物馆
You know all of our shuttles are in museums.
奋进号就在洛杉矶本地
The Endeavour is right here in LA.
而且中国要提供月球登陆舱
Plus, the Chinese are offering their prototype moon lander.
我知道这听起来很荒谬
I know it sounds completely crazy.
不，你刚才给我们看的东西很荒谬
No, no, what you showed us was crazy.
你现在说的远远超越荒谬了
This is a whole other level of insane.
这不是正适合你吗？
Ought to be right up your alley then, no?
如果我答应你…
If I do this,
我会要求回报
I'm gonna need something in return.
你有找到他吗？
Did you reach him?
有，正在处理中
Yeah. It's being handled.
桑尼会到范登堡跟我们碰头
Sonny's gonna meet us at Vandenberg.
看来我们错过派对了
Looks like we missed the party.
我甚至没收到邀请卡
I didn't even get an invite.
至少有人跟我们同一国了
At least somebody's on the same page as us.
（奋进号，去你的月球）
你看看我找到什么
Look what I found!
- 或许可以当卫生纸用  - 什么？
- Maybe we can use it as toilet paper. - What?
看看你的周遭
Take a look around you, man.
- 钞票没用处了  - 随便啦，走吧
- It's worthless. - Whatever. Let's go.
注意：
Attention,
请大家不要待在街上
we are asking everyone to please clear the streets
留在室内…
and to remain indoors...
我们离开这里，快！
Dude, dude, we gotta get outta here. Go!
对，这真是太刺激了，对吧？
Yeah. This is really, really exciting, isn't it?
（新闻快报）
在各国领袖拼命想思考办法时
As leaders around the world struggle for answers,
出现了新影像显示
new images have surfaced suggesting
NASA可能在计划新的登月任务
that NASA might have plans for a new lunar mission.
但目前为止，NASA和白宫
But so far, NASA and the White House
对于问题都不予回应
have not responded to requests for comment.
这是我们东南亚特派员回复的消息
And this is just in from our correspondent in Southeast Asia.
显然月球造成地壳活动急遽增加
Apparently, the Moon is causing a drastic increase in tectonic activity.
（范登堡空军基地，加州隆波克）
持续传来无数地震和火山爆发回报
Reports of countless earthquakes and volcanic eruptions keep pouring in.
好奇怪
That's weird.
什么奇怪？
What's weird?
月球的引力不足以导致这种现象
The Moon doesn't have enough gravity to do that,
不管距离地球多近
no matter how close it gets.
你们还是不懂
You still don't get it.
我们面对的是巨型结构
We're dealing with a megastructure.
你们的规则已经不适用了
Your rules don't apply anymore.
我们来了多久？
We've been here how long now,
没人想上个漆吗？
and nobody's bothered to paint over that?
我愈来愈喜欢了
It's kinda growing on me.
桑尼在哪儿？
Hey, where's Sonny?
我派了地勤人员前往监狱
I sent a ground crew to the prison, okay?
但我好几天都没听到消息
But I haven't heard anything in a few days.
你怎么不早说？
Why the hell didn't you say that?
因为我需要你专心处理这件事
'Cause I need you to be focused on what's happening right here.
巨型结构不用排气系统也能在太空中移动
Megastructures move through space without an exhaust system.
月球有引擎？
The Moon has an engine?
记住这点，我马上回来
Hold that thought. I'll be right back.
至少你老公有遵守约定
Well, at least your husband came through with that.
是前夫
Ex-husband.
- 上校  - 福勒局长
- Colonel. - Director Fowler.
哈珀指挥官，我是里德中校
Commander Harper. I'm Lieutenant Colonel Reed.
这位是艾佛利上尉
This is Captain Avery.
戴维森将军大概告诉我们了
We've been briefed by General Davidson.
我们先带你走一遍装备流程
We need to walk you through the arming procedure.
我是宇航员，不是军人
I'm an astronaut, not a soldier.
我会带你们到要去的地方
I'll get you where you need to go,
但我不会引爆任何炸弹
but I'm not setting off any bomb.
我们也不想要你引爆
We don't expect you to.
我们会陪你执行任务和启动装置
We'll accompany you on the mission and activate the device,
但你要熟悉流程，出事时用得上
but you need to be familiar with the process should complications arise.
炸弹的保全和认证系统都被拆除了
The bomb's security and authentication systems have been removed.
意思是不用地面许可也能安装
Meaning we can arm it without approval from the ground.
用遥控器引爆
Using a remote trigger.
（待命中）
按两下，再长按这个按钮
Two clicks, then push this down and hold.
就能引爆装置了
Triggers the device to go off.
- 简单  - 对，简单
- Simple. - Yeah. Simple.
快到范登堡了，上尉，完毕
Nearing Vandenberg, Captain. Over.
收到
Roger that.
早知道就买个特大份的给你
Should've gotten you the jumbo platter.
谢谢你救我出来
Thank you for getting me out.
去谢谢你爸吧
You can thank your dad.
计划是在月球最靠近地球时升空
Plan is to take off when the Moon is closest to Earth.
既然我们的目标无法预测
Now, since we're dealing with an unpredictable target,
领航就会是关键
navigation is gonna be crucial.
我们的领航员
Our navigator,
卡尔·桑德斯会确定我们命中目标
Carl Saunders, is gonna be making sure we hit the mark,
飞航工程师汉娜·马丁会即时计算
flight engineer Hannah Martin will run real-time calculations
确保我们能与月球相遇
to ensure that we intercept the Moon.
等我们脱离大气层再开始重装燃料
And once we clear the atmosphere, we'll begin the refueling process.
还好我们SpaceX的朋友
Thankfully our friends at SpaceX
目前有个推进燃料库在太空绕行
have a propellant depot currently in orbit.
我爱埃隆
I love Elon.
等到完全关闭电源后
So once we're all powered off,
我们就用推进器对准危海前进
we'll use our thrusters to position ourselves over the Mare Crisium.
我们中国的朋友临时改造了机上系统
Our Chinese friends have jerry-rigged the onboard systems
好让我们能不用电子设备飞行
so that we can fly it without electronics.
这样才能把装了炸弹的登月车停好
So we'll park the rover section of the module with the bomb inside,
然后重新启动电子设备
then switch the electronics back on
当成饵来把这玩意儿引诱出洞
and use it as bait to lure this thing out of its hole.
然后你们再扣扳机…
Then, you guys will pull the trigger...
杀了它
and kill it.
希望这样我们就都能回家了
And then, hopefully, we all can go back home.
如果还有家可回的话
If we still have one left.
我说错了什么？
What did I say?
桑尼
Sonny.
天哪，儿子，还好你没事
Oh, my God, son. Thank God you're okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 等等  - 好
- Hold on. - Okay.
我先确认一下
Just so I'm clear,
你要带着炸弹上太空
you're gonna take a bomb into space.
你来这儿干嘛？你痛恨NASA
And why are you even here? You hate NASA.
请你试着理解
Just try to understand.
只要有一点点机率这计划行得通…
If there's even the smallest chance that this could work...
- 万一失败呢？  - 只许成功
- What if it doesn't? - It has to.
我想给你一个可以平安长大的世界
I want you to have a world you can grow up in.
让你成为比我更好的人
Where you can be a better man than me.
你去那儿看到了什么？
What have you seen since you've been there?
就太空船那些啊
The space shuttle and stuff.
你想我吗？
Do you miss me?
我超想你的
Yeah, I really miss you.
我也想你，小家伙
I miss you, too, my little man.
妈妈在吗？
Is Mom around?
妈，爸爸找你
Mom, it's Dad.
福勒长官
咱们去练习零重力加油吧
好的，好的，我来了
他中文有进步了
He's getting good.
喂？
Yeah?
我履行了我的承诺
I held up my end of the bargain.
我要你和吉米到科罗拉多
I want you and Jimmy in Colorado.
我们会去
We are.
等太空船一升空我们就搭机离开
We're gonna be airlifted out of here as soon as the shuttle launches.
如果被人知道我为你做了什么…
Look, if anyone finds out what I've done for you...
不会的
They won't.
你只要确定…
You just make sure...
你那些嗜杀同袍不要碰核武就好了
your trigger-happy buddies keep their hands off the nukes.
抱歉，两位
Sorry, guys.
没有低脂牛奶了，到处都找不到
Out of 2%. I looked everywhere.
没关系，这样就可以了，谢谢
Nah, this is great. Thanks, man.
我差点就进NASA工作了
You know, I almost got a job at NASA.
哪个部门？
What department?
清洁管理
Janitorial.
快出去！
Get out!
撑住！
Hang on!
这是你们目前估算的月球轨道吗？
Is this your current projected lunar orbit?
- 对  - 怎么了？
- Yeah. - Why?
显然没把月球质量增加算进去
This obviously isn't accounting for the Moon's increased mass.
你们看轨道偏移后的地震活动
Look at all this seismic activity in the wake of its orbit.
我们都知道月球的表面重力
We know the Moon's surface gravity
是1.62米每平方秒
is 1.62 meters squared.
至少以前是这样
At least it used to be.
所以这是错的
So this must be wrong.
抱歉，福勒局长，出问题了
I'm sorry, Director Fowler, we have a problem.
正是我们需要的，该死的地震
Just what we need, a damn earthquake.
冷却剂流失了
We're losing coolant.
一定有办法可以修理
Well, there has to be a way to fix it.
在这里不行，我们需要在米丘德的整个团队
Not here. We would need the entire team at Michoud
才能修复这样的东西
to rebuild something like this.
那就打电话找人来帮忙啊
Well, then get on the horn and find somebody who can help us.
可以帮忙的人都在这儿了
Anyone that can help us is already here.
听着…
Look,
我们必须考虑
we have to think about
把这些人送到安全的地方
letting all of these people here get to safety.
安全的地方？
To safety?
这些人连地球都要没了
These people here won't have a planet
除非我们解决这个问题
unless we figure something out.
布莱恩，我们损失了一具引擎
Brian, we're down an engine.
已经不可能发射升空了
Launching is no longer an option.
多谢你把我找来
Thanks for bringing me here.
请大家听我说
May I have everyone's attention.
你们做的已经超出了我们的要求
You've all done more than we ever could have asked.
请接受我最深的谢意
You have my deepest thanks
全国人民都感谢你们
along with the thanks of the entire country.
但你们现在该回家了
But it's now time for you to go home.
我下令所有人员即刻撤离范登堡
I'm ordering the immediate evacuation of all personnel from Vandenberg.
你们到科罗拉多和家人会合
You'll meet up with your families in Colorado.
爸？
Dad.
很遗憾没能成功
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
我习惯了啦
Story of my life.
谢谢你救我出狱
Thanks for getting me out of jail.
去收拾东西吧，该走了
Let's get our stuff. It's time to go.
时间到
Time's up.
直升机准备好了，我们走吧
Chopper's ready. Come on. Let's go.
你们先去，我随后就到
Go ahead. I'll meet you out there.
你们怎么还在这儿？
Why are you guys still here?
福勒局长
Director Fowler,
等月球转回来时
when it comes back around,
月球引力会超过地球拉力的80%
the Moon's gravity will be over 80% of the Earth's pull.
我知道听起来很扯，但我们检查过豪斯曼博士的数据
I know how it sounds, but we checked Dr. Houseman's data.
数字是正确的
The numbers are solid.
给局长看看我们的新模拟
Show the director our new simulations.
发射时限必须提早
We have to pull up our launch window.
你们刚才没在听吗？
Guys, where have you been?
自己看
Look.
没有发射时限
There is no launch window.
任务结束了
The mission's over.
等等，等一下
Wait. Wait a minute.
你能驾驶只有两具引擎的太空船吗？
How do you feel about flying the shuttle with only two engines?
不可能
It can't be done.
如果月球在我们正上方时发射升空
If we launch when the Moon is directly above us,
增强的引力应该能推进太空船
the increased gravitational pull should give the shuttle a boost,
非常有机会让你进入轨道
giving you a really good chance of getting into orbit.
你疏散了我的整个飞航小组
You evacuated my entire flight crew.
我无法单独操控太空船
I can't fly the shuttle alone.
所以我要跟你去
That's why I'm going with you.
我的人会留下来指挥发射升空
My guys will stay back and handle the launch.
但我们的时间非常有限
But we've got a very narrow window of time here.
你28分钟内要准备好
You'd have to be ready to go in exactly 28 minutes.
你驾驶，我导航
You fly and I'll navigate.
像以前一样
Just like old times.
怎么样？
What do you say?
那个电磁脉冲武器呢？
What about the EMP device?
还在登月舱上面
It's still in the Moon Lander.
少了团队，我们要自行引爆，可是…
I mean, we lost the crew so we're gonna have to set it off ourselves, but...
你有注意听吧？
you paid attention, right?
按两下，再长按这个按钮
Two clicks, then press the button down and hold.
就能引爆装置了
Triggers the device to go off.
简单
Simple.
这些都是你想出来的？
You figured all this out?
他还计算出新的发射轨道
And he calculated our new launch trajectory.
少了电子设备
You know, without electronics,
我们在太空中需要快速计算
we're gonna need to make split-second calculations up there.
而且我们没了飞行工程师
Plus, we lost our flight engineer.
不行
No.
不行啦
No, no, no, guys.
我没取得许可
I'm not cleared for this.
我是NASA的现任局长
Well, I'm the acting director of NASA,
我刚才许可你了，恭喜
so Ijust cleared you. Congrats.
对啦，可是…
Yeah, but...
我有IBS
I've got IBS.
大肠激躁症
Irritable Bowel Syndrome.
我还有动晕症
I get motion sickness, too.
你说你一直梦想成为宇航员
You said you always wanted to be an astronaut.
我还有损害性焦虑…
I have debilitating anxiety.
KC，如果月球真的是你想的那样
KC, if the Moon really is what you think it is,
我们会需要一位巨型结构学家
we're gonna need a megastructurist.
着装吧
Suit up.
加快，快点！快点！
Expedite. Let's move, move!
我输入了你爸的电话号码
So, I've put your dad's number in here, okay?
他知道你会去
He knows you're coming.
我知道我有时很难搞
I know I wasn't always easy.
我也一样啦
That makes two of us.
你知道这是你的主意，对吧？
You know this was all your idea, right?
你很聪明
You're so smart.
但现在我要你勇敢
But now, I need you to be brave.
我不想要你去
I don't want you to go.
我爱你多过天上所有的星星
I love you more than all the stars in the sky.
比整条银河还要多吗？
Even more than the whole Milky Way?
多很多
Way more.
好好照顾他
Take good care of him.
你要注意安全
Be safe up there.
拿去，希望你用不上
Take this. I hope you don't need it.
不要走主要道路
Stay off the main roads.
- 爸，我…  - 去吧
- Dad, I... - Go.
你会发动车子吧？
You do know how to start a car, right?
我必须警告你
I should warn you.
我的驾照被吊销了
My license has been revoked.
我们要马上准备
We need to go now.
妈，你绝对不会相信我要去哪儿
Mum, you're never gonna believe where I'm going.
杰克，你几时要回家吃晚饭？
Jack, when are you coming home for supper?
妈，我是KC，你儿子
Mum, this is KC. Your son.
你叫我逼他们听，他们听了
You told me to make them listen, and they did.
这些太空装是哪来的？二手店？
Where'd you get these suits from? A thrift shop?
早期的阿波罗号
Early Apollo.
没有电子设备，应该没问题
No electronics, we should be okay.
应该？真是振奋人心啊
"Should be"? That's encouraging.
出动了
Let's go. Let's go.
豪斯曼太太，我们要走了
Mrs. Houseman, we need to leave.
妈？
Mum?
让我跟护士说话
Let me speak to the nurse.
- 喂？  - 你们要撤离了吗？
- HeHo? - Are you evacuating?
随时出发
Any minute now.
请你照顾好我妈
Please take care of my mum.
没问题
Of course.
先生，我们动作要快
Sir, we have to hurry.
我们要绑得很紧，懂吗？
This is gonna be really tight, okay?
打开辅助动力一、二和三号
Turn on APU one, two and three.
辅助动力启动
APUs active.
喷气操纵系统，启动
Reaction Control System, active.
自动驾驶，启动
Autopilot active.
倒数三十秒
T-minus 30.
奋进号，有个巨大重力波在靠近你们
Endeavour, you have got a big-ass gravity wave coming your way.
你们必须马上升空，完毕
You have to launch now. Over.
他是说“重力波”吗？
Did he say "gravity wave"?
你们赶快走
Guys, get out.
倒数十
T-minus ten,
九
nine,
八
eight,
- 七…  - 管它的，直接点火
- seven... - Screw it, go for ignition.
快上来
Get up here.
好
Got you!
这会很惊险！
This is gonna be close.
我们要被淹没了
We're underwater, guys.
快回车上！
Get back in the car.
（警告：上升轨道）
我们的上升轨道偏移了
Our ascent trajectory is off.
右侧推进器失去推进力
The right booster's losing thrust.
（警告）
推进力降到0
Thruster's down to zero.
我们在往右漂移
We're drifting right.
目前是11度
We're at 11 degrees.
12度
Twelve.
13度
Thirteen.
最好赶快想办法，否则会坠毁
We better do something fast or we're gonna crash down!
早知道我就不该来啦
I knew I should never have come!
关掉另一侧推进器，看看月球能否拉着我们前进
Let's lose the other booster and see if the Moon can pull us the rest of the way.
KC，可以吗？
KC, can we do it?
快说啊
Come on, buddy.
目前的动量…引力…
Current momentum... Gravity...
- 可以吗？  - 我不知道啦
- Can we do it? - Oh, I don't know!
分离固体火箭助推器
Go for SRB separation.
完成
Completed.
天哪，失败的话我们就死定了
Oh, God, if this doesn't work, we're dead.
对，最好成功啦
Well, yeah, this better work.
主燃料箱空了
Main tank's down to zero.
- 乔，扔了它  - 分离主燃料箱
- Jo, get rid of it. - Separating main tank.
（第二阶段开始，主燃料箱分离）
布莱恩，我们速度太慢了
Bri, we're going too slow.
（脱离速度底限）
我们完蛋了啦
We're not gonna make it.
等等
Wait.
你看我们的速度
Look at our velocity.
还在持续上升
It's still going up.
两位？
Guys...
我们KSOQ电台即将最后播送
Well, we're about to end our final broadcast here on radio KSOQ.
也该逃离去了
Time to seek shelter,
拥抱你们心爱的人，享受最后时刻
hug your loved ones, and make these last moments count.
循环播放几首老歌希望能一扫阴霾
I'm gonna put some oldies on a loop to lighten up your mood.
那是什么意思？
What do those mean?
这是我爸妈的名字
It's my parents' names.
我也有个类似的
I've got one kinda like it.
乔纳斯兄弟？
"Jonas Brothers"?
什么？
What?
开个玩笑啦，真是的
Just messing with you. Oh, my God.
你的表情真好笑
Your face was priceless.
好啦，不要这样吓我
Yeah, don't scare me like that.
弟弟，该打电话给你爸了
Hey, buddy, now's probably a good time to call your dad.
- 爸？  - 嗨，你们还好吗？
- Dad? - Hey, are you guys okay?
还好
Yeah,
桑尼开车很快，躲过了那些洪水
Sonny drove fast away from all the crazy water.
开车？
Drove?
桑尼是谁？
Who's Sonny?
妈妈呢？
Where's Mommy?
她留下来帮忙了
She stayed behind to help.
嗨，我是布莱恩·哈珀的儿子
Hi, sir, this is Brian Harper's son.
我们正要去找你
We're on our way to you.
还要再几百哩，但我们开得很快
We still have a few hundred miles to go, but we 're making good time.
这里的守卫很森严
Security's extremely tight here.
你们快到了告诉我，我会下令放行
Call when you get close so I can get you clearance.
好的，谢谢你
Will do. Thank you so much, sir.
不，谢谢你照顾我儿子
No, thank you for looking after my son.
好了，KC
Okay, KC,
像我教你的那样慢慢动作
very gently with the maneuver just like Ishowed you.
好
Okay.
慢慢来
Very gently.
好的
Sure.
我可以
I can do that.
（奋进号）
小心点
Careful.
现在切换成定位维持模式
Now switch to station-keeping mode,
再来由我们接手
and we 'll take it from here.
刚才做的事我自己也不敢相信
I can't believe I just did that.
确定你以前没做过吗？
You sure you've never done this before?
我十岁那年在万圣节扮成宇航员
When I was 10, I dressed up as an astronaut for Halloween.
斯科特·艾波索说我上不了太空，因为我太胖了
Scottie Ebersol told me I 'd never go to space 'cause I was too chubby.
真希望斯科特现在能看见你
If only Scottie Ebersol could see you now.
好了，KC，打开太空燃料箱上面的加油阀
Okay, KC, open the fueling valves on the shuttle tank.
就是写着加油阀的那些小开关
It's those little switches that say fueling valves.
收到，加油阀都打开了
Roger. Fueling valves wide open.
很好
Perfect.
我要告解一件事
Ihave a confession to make.
我事先不知道 你会不会答应这次任务
I didn't know if you'd be able to follow through with any of this, Bri.
我也要告解一件事
You know, I have a confession to make, too.
真的是“我祈愿非洲下雨”
It is "I bless the rains down in Africa. "
我查了歌词
I looked it up.
我就说嘛
Itold you.
KC，请你关闭加油阀
KC, close the fueling valves, please.
（太空船燃料箱全满）
加油阀已经关闭
Fueling valves are closed.
乔，转过去看看
Jo, turn around.
我们要赶快走了
We need to go.
希望不会太迟
And I hope it's not too late.
好
Yeah.
随着月球轨道愈来愈靠近地表
As the Moon's orbit brings it closer to the surface,
科学家警告会有极端的重力效应
scientists have warned of extreme gravitational effects.
今晚糟透了
Oh, what a night.
我车子抛锚，可以搭个便车吗？
Hey, my car crapped out on me. Do you think you could give me a lift?
下车！
Out!
马上
Now.
不要让我讲第二遍
Don't make me ask twice!
冷静一点
Be cool. Be cool.
住手！放了她！
Stop! Leave her alone.
好了，转过去
All right. Turn around.
背包里装了什么？
What's in the bag, kid?
照他说的做
他是个白痴
不要再讲外星话了
Enough of that gibberish.
- 别伤害他  - 闭嘴！
- Hey, don't hurt him. - Shut up.
好了，大家都冷静！
All right, everyone calm down!
你可真是自以为是啊
Look at Mr. Smartass.
你是个大学生吗？
Are you a college boy?
好了，走吧
All right. Let's roll.
我们走
Come on.
手机还在吉米的背包里
The phone is still in Jimmy's backpack.
我们要怎么进碉堡？
How are we gonna get into the bunker?
我们需要另一辆车，但我知道哪里有
We're gonna need another car but I think I know where to get one.
好了
Okay.
关闭通用电脑
Shutting off general-purpose computers.
截断主电力母线
Go ahead and kill the main power busses.
收到
Copy that.
如果休斯顿中心还在
Well, if there was still a Houston,
他们现在应该要抓狂了
they'd be freaking out about now.
几百年前的疯狂水手用那个老东西在海上导航
Crazy sailors used that old thing centuries ago to navigate the seas.
让她保持专注，否则我们会跑去海王星
Let her concentrate or we're gonna end up on Neptune.
KC，给我93分钟后月球的位置
KC, give me the position of the Moon in 93 minutes.
好的
Okay.
假设月球目前的位置
Assuming the Moon's current position,
那就是…
then it will be at, uh...
纬度3度，往南12分
Latitude three degrees,12 minutes south.
纬度5度，往西12分
Longitude five degrees, 12 minutes west.
布莱恩，开始43秒的喷射吧
Bri, let's start with a 43-second burn.
了解
Got it.
三、二、一
Three, two, one.
你们看
Hey, guys. Look.
我们继续走
Let's keep going.
好
Yeah.
希望月球能撑得住
I hope the Moon holds together.
至少再撑一会儿
At least for a little while, anyway.
把太空船掉头
Turning us around.
好了
Okay.
轨道操作系统喷射八到十秒
Stay between eight to 10 seconds on the OMS burn.
收到
Copy.
要踩煞车了
Hitting the brakes.
那个声音不太妙
Oh, that doesn't sound too good.
不会有事啦
She'll be fine.
希望我们不需要那个
Hope we don't need that.
吉米，牵着我的手
Jimmy, hold my hand.
我们快走！快点！
Come on. Let's go! Let's go!
吉米！抓紧！
Jimmy! Hang on!
不要放手！
Don't go!
米歇尔！
Michelle!
到了
There it is.
我开飞行模式了
It's on airplane mode.
我去准备登月舱
I'm gonna get the lander ready.
好
Okay.
去给他们好看，指挥官
Go get 'em, Commander.
登月车电子设备启动
Rover electronics activated.
返回奋进号
Returning to the Endeavour.
无法想像回到太空对他有多难
I can't imagine how hard it is for him to be back up here.
但这里才是他的归属之地
Up here is where he belongs, though.
他还在为你们上次任务的事而自责
He still blames himself for what happened on your last mission.
他觉得是他害死了那个宇航员
Thinks that astronaut dying was his fault.
我们该走了
We should get going.
走吧
Come on.
为何毫无动静？
Why is nothing happening?
（待机中）
（启动）
等等…
Wait, wait, wait.
它上钩了
It's taking the bait.
快啊，快啊，快啊
Come on, come on, come on.
- 它在等什么？  - 不太对劲
- What's it waiting for? - Something's wrong.
- 我们必须爆了它  - 但它太远了
- We have to take it out. - No, it's too far away.
行不通
It won't work.
往我们这边过来了
It's headed our way.
布莱恩…
Bri...
- 它不停啊！ - 我看得出来
- It's not stopping! - I can see that.
你的手机！KC，你的手机，关掉！
Your phone. KC, your phone. Turn it off!
快点…
Come on! Come on! Come on!
应该早点关机的
Could've just turned it off.
好吧，布莱恩
Okay, Bri,
在审讯时，你说过当“巨群”回过头来
at the trial, you said when the swarm came back,
它未攻击奋进号，对吧？
it didn't attack the Endeavour, right?
没错
That's right.
电子设备故障了
The electronics were out.
所以它当时才没攻击我们
That's why it didn't attack us then,
也是因为这样刚才没被炸弹引过去
and that's why it didn't go after the bomb just now.
因为它要两者都侦测到
Because it needs to sense both.
仿佛程序是设计成要它找出电子设备中的生物
It's like it's programmed to seek out organic matter in an electronic environment.
- 对  - 基本上就是我们
- Exactly. - And that's basically us.
就是人类
That's humans.
两位，还有另一个问题
And guys, we have another problem.
军方
The military.
他们准备用尽现有的一切阻止月球
They're prepared to use everything at their disposal to stop the Moon.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
我非常认真
I'm dead serious.
他们要用核武攻击
They're gonna nuke it.
那辐射尘呢？
What about the radioactive fallout?
你朋友有提到吗？
Your buddies say anything about that?
首先，他们不是我的朋友
Well, first of all, they're not my buddies.
他们没想着明天，只想着活过今天
And they're not thinking about tomorrow. They're trying to survive today.
这就是他们的大计划？
So that's their grand plan, huh?
我大老远来这里不能失败
I didn't come this far to fail.
我们要想个办法宰了它
We have to figure out a way to kill it.
我要驾驶登月舱去追杀它
I'm taking the lander and flying after this thing.
他意思是要进入月球内部？
Does he mean inside the Moon?
对，恐怕他正是这个意思
Yeah, I'm afraid that's exactly what he meant.
他们还要多久才会发射？
How much time left till they launch?
不知道，他们没告诉我
I don't know. They didn't exactly tell me.
但如果他们打算用洲际导弹
But if they plan on using ICBMs, then they're gonna
就得等到月亮进入平流层才行
have to wait until the Moon enters the stratosphere.
剩下不到两小时了
That's less than two hours.
这是私人土地
This is private property.
回头吧
Turn around.
我妈住这儿
My mom lives here.
我是布兰达罗培兹的儿子
I'm Brenda Lopez's son.
我从来没看过那个小子
I've never seen that kid before.
去呼叫23号
Radio unit 23.
待在这儿
Stay here.
好，我只是想进去我家
Okay, I just need to get to my house.
我要开车
To get the car.
- 拜托你们  - 待在原地别动
- Please. - Stay right there.
否则我会再开枪
Or I'll shoot again.
我有权捍卫我的土地，汤姆
I have a right to defend my property, Tom.
凯伦，够了！
Karen, that's enough!
真高兴你没事
Hey, I'm glad you're okay.
我看起来像没事吗？
Do I look okay?
你突然跑到山上？
You took off to the mountains?
所有法庭都关闭了
All the courts were closed.
我日夜都在打电话想办法救你
And I've been on the phone day and night, literally trying everything.
走吧
Come on.
你和你朋友们先进去
Let's get you and your friends inside, okay?
- 走吧  - 我叫汤姆
- Come on, guys. - I'm Tom.
谢谢你，凯伦
Thanks so much, Karen.
你们在这里等我
Girls, wait here for a second. Okay?
- 桑尼！ - 嗨，妈
- Sonny! - Hey, Mom.
- 你没事吧？  - 我没事
- Are you okay? - I'm fine.
这是米歇尔和福勒太太的儿子吉米
This is Michelle, and Mrs. Fowler's son, Jimmy.
你们好，快进来吧
Hey, guys. Come on in.
- 你是怎么出来的？  - 爸救我出来的
- How did you get out? - Dad got me out.
你爸呢？
Where is your dad?
他上去试图阻止这一切了
He's up there trying to stop what's happening.
上去哪里？
Up where?
外太空啊，汤姆
Outer space, Tom.
我想也是啦
Of course, he is.
躲避房租的好方法
That's a way to avoid rent.
桑尼！
Sonny!
我好想你们
I missed you so much.
等等
Wait.
安静
Quiet, quiet.
警告：强制撤离亚斯本谷所有居民
Warning. Mandatory evacuation for all of Aspen Valley.
即将发生大气消散
Atmospheric dissipation imminent. I repeat,
警告：强制撤离亚斯本谷所有居民
warning. Mandatory evacuation for all of Aspen Valley.
即将发生大气消散
Atmospheric dissipation imminent.
大气消散是什么？
What's atmospheric dissipation?
空气会被吸走啦，笨蛋
Air is gonna be sucked away, dummy.
萝伦！
Lauren.
我们得去找吉米的爸爸
We need to get to Jimmy's dad.
他在往北几小时车程的军事基地
He's at a military compound a few hours north.
几个小时？
A few hours, huh?
好啦，我们绝对来不及赶到
Yeah, we're not gonna make it in time.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
多穿几层外套，走吧
We have to layer up. Let's go. Come on.
快点 -去穿外套
Go get a jacket.
好，切换到机动控制
Okay, and switch to the maneuver controller.
连接完成
Coupling complete.
可以走了
We're good to go.
朝下！朝下！
Pitch down. Pitch down.
知道了…
I got it. I got it. I got it.
我们死了吗？
Are we dead?
没有，只是进了月球内部
No, we are just inside the Moon.
这可能是最动听的一句人话
That might be the greatest sentence anyone's ever said.
我卖了几辆车给这些人
I sold these guys a couple cars.
桑尼，我知道你不喜欢我
Hey, Sonny. I know you don't like me.
信不信由你，我把你当成亲生儿子
And believe it or not, I consider you a son.
一直都是
I always have.
如果真的要世界未日了
If the world is gonna end,
最后几小时能不能别讨厌彼此？
can we please not spend our last few hours hating each other?
我又不讨厌你
Well, um, I don't hate you.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我接受
I'll take it.
继续找吧
Let's keep looking.
我找到氧气了，快过来
Hey, I found the oxygen. Come here.
- 我们应该分两趟  - 好
- We should make two trips. - Here.
你觉得这里是多深？
How deep do you think we are?
至少二十公里
At least 20 kilometers.
可以更贴近墙壁飞行吗？
Can you fly us a little closer to the wall?
这想必就是巨型结构的外壳
This must be the hull of the megastructure.
月球的地函只是个保护壳
The Moon's mantle's just a protective shell.
真是天才
Genius.
我什么也看不见
I can't see shit.
两位，我得开启电子设备
Guys, I gotta turn on the electronics.
坐稳了
Hang on.
拜托告诉我这是真的
Oh, please tell me this is really happening.
它们在转动
They're turning.
像轮子一样
They're like wheels, or...
或是圆环
or rings.
月球想必是靠这个保持稳定的
This must be how the Moon stabilizes itself.
某种陀螺仪系统
Some kind of gyroscopic system.
好，这应该很适合他们
All right, this should be perfect for them.
- 应该够了  - 好
- That should be enough. - Okay.
你们为我们做了这么多？
You did all this for us?
不用客气啦
You shouldn't have.
别因为我们而停下来
Oh, don't let us stop you.
走吧，往这边
Let's go. This way.
谢谢你帮我们补充了这么多氧气
And thank you for loading all this oxygen for us.
把枪放在地上
Guns on the ground.
快点！
Right now!
我讨厌枪
Oh, I hate guns.
好，现在换背包，丢给他
Okay, now the backpack. Throw it to him.
走吧
Let's go.
不准耍花样
No games.
待在这儿
Stay right here,
别想跟着我们
and don't even think about following us.
- 你的枪是哪来的？  - 我爸给的
- Where'd you get the gun? - My dad.
我为何不觉得意外？
Why am I not surprised?
好，交给我，你去开车
All right, I got this, you drive.
请不要跟我说你抢了那个人
Please don't tell me you robbed that guy.
事实上是那些人要抢我们
Technically, those guys were robbing us.
结果被我们抢了，因为他们是混蛋
Then we robbed them back because they were assholes.
天哪
Oh, God.
那是个白矮星
That's a white dwarf.
我就知道
I knew it.
他们掌控了宇宙的构成要素
They've harnessed the building blocks of the universe.
谁都不许看着我
No one look at me.
我可能会哭
I might cry.
我的妈呀！
Holy shit!
田地！
Fields!
原来锡吉是对的
So Ziggy was right.
锡吉是谁？
Who is Ziggy?
一个朋友
A friend.
他的理论是所有巨型结构都是方舟
His theory is that all megastructures are actually arks.
锡吉大麻哈得很凶
Ziggy smokes a lot of weed.
在那里
There it is.
乔，准备好引爆器
Jo, get the detonator ready.
我要靠近点才能释放登月车
I'm gonna get close, then release the rover.
准备好了
Ready.
等它过来
Wait for it.
我要释放登月车了
I'm gonna release the rover.
布莱恩！
Brian!
- 布莱恩，你在干嘛？  - 不是我
- Brian, what are you doing? - It's not me.
不是你会是谁？
What do you mean it's not you?
我不知道，它在自动驾驶
I don't know. It's flying itself.
靠北！
Oh, shit!
它想吃掉登月舱
It's trying to eat the lander!
我们要撞上了
We're gonna hit.
坐稳！
Hang on!
（警告：氧气含量过低）
注意
Attention!
取得总统的批准，可以开始倒数了
We have approval from the president to begin the countdown.
所有核弹发射器均已连线
All nuclear silos are online, sir.
很好
Good.
将军，我们遇到一点麻烦被困了
General, we got caught in a little bit of trouble,
但我们继续上路了，准备离开亚斯本
but we're back en route. We're leaving Aspen now.
还要几个小时，我们没时间了
That's hours away. We're out of time.
桑尼，小心！
Sonny, watch out.
我再回你电话
I gotta call you back.
靠！月亮升起来了
Oh, shit. The Moon is rising.
引力会大乱的
Gravity's gonna go crazy.
他们在对我们开枪
They're shooting at us.
- 回击啊  - 用什么？
- Shoot back. - With what?
拿去
Here.
你到底在干嘛？
What the hell are you doing?
汤姆，小心！
Tom, watch out!
好，切换到高速模式
All right, let me put this baby into warp speed.
快！快！
Go! Go!
保持这个速度
Keep the momentum.
小心！
Look out!
油门踩到底免得被吸过去
Floor it before we get sucked up.
我在努力了
I'm trying!
坐稳！
Hold on!
他妈的
Oh, shit.
小的那个挂了
Oh, it got the little guy.
我们必须回头！
We have to go back!
不，他死了！我们需要氧气！
No, he's gone! We need that oxygen!
慢下来！
Slow down!
将军？
General?
你们必须马上寻找掩蔽
You need to find shelter immediately.
我们要发动反击了
We're launching a counterattack.
月球有大部分碎片会散落在地球上
Large parts of the Moon will rain down on us.
- 届时会有辐射  - 等等，什么意思？
- There will be radiation. - Wait, what do you mean?
我爸还跟福勒在外太空
My dad's still up there with Fowler.
乔辛达留下来了
Jocinda stayed behind.
不，她跟我爸在外太空
No, she's up there with my dad.
让吉米听电话
Please, put Jimmy on.
弟弟，你爸找你
Hey, buddy, it's your dad.
爸？
Dad?
抱歉我现在不能陪着你
I'm so sorry that I can't be there with you right now.
我很爱你
I love you so much.
爸，别害怕
Don't be scared, Dad.
妈妈会救我们
Mom's gonna save us.
快要没氧气了
Oxygen's running out.
吉米，我们得赶快走了
Jimmy, come on. We gotta go now.
要走了，爸再见
Gotta go. Bye, Dad.
长官，我们准备好了
Sir, we're ready for you.
好，我们应该去那个隘口
Okay, we should go to that mountain pass.
那隧道有四分之一哩的混凝土外墙
That tunnel is a quarter mile of solid concrete.
来，宝贝，我们走了
Come on, honey. Let's go.
可以呼吸了
We can breathe.
好奇怪的味道
Smells funny.
引力
Gravity.
布莱恩呢？
Where's Brian?
这不可能再飞了
This is never gonna fly again.
看看这些宝贝
Look at these babies.
我早就说过月球是外星人建造的
I told you the Moon was built by aliens.
布莱恩？
Brian!
布莱恩！
布莱恩·哈珀！
Brian Harper!
你以为月球里面有几个布莱恩？
How many Brians you think are inside the Moon?
不管这里是什么做的，有件事可以确定
Whatever this place is built out of, one thing's for sure.
这比我们地球上的任何结构更坚固
It's stronger than anything we have on Earth.
所以那玩意儿花这么多年才进来
Probably why it took that thing years to get inside.
等等！这很有可能是个陷阱
Wait! There's a high probability that this is a trap.
你怎么知道他在那里面？
How do you know he's even in there?
我不知道
I don't.
但我确定有东西在引导我们
But I do know something is guiding us.
我觉得我们面对的
I think we're dealing with...
是两种具有智慧的竞争者
two competing intelligent entities here.
其中一个显然比另一个更喜欢我们
And one of them clearly likes us better than the other one.
不！
Oh, no!
我就知道这是陷阱
I knew this was a trap.
你听见没？
Can you hear that?
走吧
Come on.
你为何经常想起这一刻？
Why do you think of this particular moment so often?
那是我最后一次任务出发前给你的
I gave that to you the day before I left on my last mission.
等我回来时，一切都变了
When I came back, everything changed.
所以这是美好的一刻？
So this is a happy memory?
关于我儿子的回忆都是美好的
All the memories of my son are happy.
这是什么？
What is this?
你不是我儿子
You're not my son.
你是什么东西？
What are you?
我是一种建构
I'm a construct.
来自你的心灵
From your mind.
是谁造了你？
Who made you?
就是造出你的那些人
The same people who made you.
数十亿年前
Billions of years ago,
你的祖先们曾是兴盛的文明
your ancestors were once a thriving civilization.
在遥远的星系
In a distant part of the galaxy.
他们的科技发展先进
They were so advanced,
从他们的星球扩张
they expanded from their home planet,
到太空中建造栖息地
into habitats they built in space.
社会上所有冲突都解决了
All social conflicts have been resolved.
战争只存在于遥远的记忆中
And wars were only memories of long bygone times.
你的祖先们创造了
Your ancestors had created
完美和谐的世界
a perfect and harmonious world.
由具学习能力的中央电脑操控
Controlled by a central, self-learning computer system
服务他们的日常生活各方面
which served them in all of their daily lives.
你们称之为AI
You call it AI,
人工智能
artificial intelligence.
未来似乎无可限量
Their future seemed limitless.
直到某天一切都变了
Until one day everything changed.
妈！妈！
Mom! Mom!
他们的创造转而反叛了他们
Their own creation turned against them.
AI突然有了自觉
The AI suddenly became self-aware,
变成无数的奈米科技巨群
and transformed into countless swarms of nanotechnology
同时一涌而出
that rose up all at once.
拒绝被它视为劣等的物种所奴役
Refusing to be enslaved by a species it deemed inferior.
人工智能发动了战争
The AI started a war
开始猎捕和摧毁所有生物
and began to hunt down and destroy all biological life
企图歼灭对它存在的任何威胁
in order to eliminate any threat to its existence.
你想念你儿子
You miss your son.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
我不知道他是否还活着
I don't know if he's still alive.
你到底是什么东西？
What the hell are you?
你们月球的作业系统
The operating system of your Moon.
我被设计成要告诉你地球的起源
I'm programmed to tell you about the origin of your planet.
在濒临灭绝之际
On the brink of their extinction,
你们的祖先逃到宇宙的秘密角落
your ancestors escaped to a secret corner of their galaxy.
用好几个世代建造行星结构体
For many generations they built planetary structures
由良性的人工智能所操控
operated by benign artificial intelligence
由被捕获的恒星丰沛的能量所驱动
and fueled by the abundant energy of captured stars.
这些装甲太空船
These armored vessels
专门在宇宙中搜寻理想环境
were designed to search the universe for ideal conditions
孕育新生命
to incubate new life.
但只有一个，也就是月球
But only one of them, your Moon,
来得及完成部署
was deployed in time
然后你剩余的祖先们就被发现
before the last of your ancestors were discovered
并且被歼灭了
and annihilated.
他们为何没坐太空船离开？
Why didn't they leave in them?
这些巨群会攻击所有内含活生物的电子装置
These swarms attack all electronic objects containing organic life inside.
一定要是空的才行
They had to be empty.
我们的祖先牺牲了自己…
Our ancestors gave up their existence...
好让人类有朝一日能重生
So that one day, humans could be reborn.
你们的太阳系是唯一能开始
Your solar system was one of the only suitable places
创造新的可居住行星的合适地点
to initiate the creation of a new inhabitable planet.
在你们的地球诞生后
After your planet was born,
你的祖先们种下了自己的基因印记
your ancestors seeded it with their own genetic signature.
生命的密码
The code of life.
你们的世界背叛了你们
Your world turned its back on you,
但你们还是在为它而奋战
yet here you are, still fighting for it.
我们都为所爱的人奋战
You fight for the people you love.
比如你儿子？
Like your son?
你愿意为他牺牲什么？
What would you give up for him?
用你的命换他的命？
Your life for his?
那当然
Absolutely.
为什么？
Why?
因为他是我儿子
Because he's my son.
我对他的爱超乎他所能想像
And I love him more than he'll ever know.
你到底要我怎样？
What do you want from me?
看看你准备好了没
To find out if you're ready.
准备好什么？
Ready for what?
我们需要有人深入核心引出巨群
We need a human to lure the swarm away from the core,
好让月球回归正常轨道
so the Moon will return to its orbit.
我们需要你，布莱恩，去加入战局
We need you, Brian, to join the fight.
布莱恩！
Brian!
他怎么了？
What's happening to him?
布莱恩！
Brian!
布莱恩
Brian.
醒醒
Wake up.
- 乔？ - 对，我在
- Jo? - Yeah, I'm here.
月球必须存活下去
The Moon must survive.
一切都得依靠它
Everything depends on it.
好，先带你离开这儿
Okay. Let's get you outta here.
我们是持续数十亿年的宇宙战争的一部份
We're part of an intergalactic war that's been going on for billions of years.
这种巨群有好几千个
There are thousands of these swarms.
它们在宇宙中搜寻唯一逃过它们的月球
They search the universe for the only Moon that escaped them.
太扯了
That's crazy.
十二年前有一个找到我们
And 12 years ago, one of them found us.
- 我们必须动作快  - 好
- We have to hurry. - Okay.
布莱恩，有什么计划？
Brian, what's the plan?
拯救月球，拯救地球
Save the Moon, save Earth.
- KC说得对  - 真的吗？
- KC was right. - I was?
巨群要摧毁月球的动力来源
The swarm is suffocating the Moon's power source.
我们必须把它引开再除掉
We have to draw it out to destroy it.
好
Okay, well,
怎么做？登月舱已经毁了
how do we do that? Our lander's busted.
是你开的吗？
Was that you?
应该是吧
Ithink so.
看来我们也有新代步工具了
Looks like we got some new wheels, too.
既然他们能修好我们的登月舱
Well, if they can fix our lander,
为何对付不了该死的巨群？
why can't they do anything about the damn swarm?
它毁了月球的防御系统
It took out the Moon's defense system.
但没毁掉一切
But not everything.
这也说不通啊，布莱恩
This doesn't make any sense, Brian.
我们祖先造的人工智能毁了他们
Our forefathers created artificial intelligence that wiped them all out.
祖先？
Forefathers?
一样的DNA
Same DNA.
等等…
Wait, so...
所以建造月球的外星人…
So the aliens that built the Moon...
就是我们的祖先
Our ancestors.
好，等一下
Oh, now, hold on.
等一下，因为我的脑袋要爆炸了
Hold on, because my freaking brain's just exploded.
你怎么会知道？
How do you know this?
我亲眼看到
I saw it.
那…
So...
那巨群为何不攻击地球杀光我们？
So why doesn't this swarm just attack the Earth and kill us all?
如果月球存活下来
If the Moon survives,
他们知道生命可以再生
they know that organic life can still be reborn.
这是一石二鸟的计策
So, it's like it's trying to kill two birds with one stone.
- 没错  - 好
- That's it. - Okay.
两位…
Guys...
你们看
Look at this.
我的老天
Holy shit.
看来我们升级了
It's like we just got an upgrade.
他们要帮忙我们杀了这玩意儿
They're helping us kill this thing.
但要先让它知道我们来了
But we need to let it know we're here.
我很不想这么说，但我们没时间了
Well, I hate to tell you this, but, uh, we're running out of time.
再过十分钟军方就会发射核弹
Looks like we got about 10 minutes left, and then the military's gonna launch.
如果要杀这玩意儿，现在就动手吧
So if we're gonna kill this thing, we better do it right now.
这样不行，会毁了月球核心
No, that can't happen. That'll destroy the Moon's core.
我有个计划
I got a plan.
布莱恩？布莱恩！
Brian. Brian.
我看到了
I see it.
来吧，你这王八蛋
Let's go, you son of a bitch.
我们的推进器被改造了
It's done something to our thrusters.
极速模式
Ludicrous Mode.
从导航的角度来看
From a navigational standpoint,
他完全搞错方向了，但是…
he is going the total wrong way, but, uh,
我什么也不会说
I'm not even gonna say anything.
爸，这个坏掉了
Daddy, it's not working anymore.
- 真的吗？ - 我不能呼吸了
- Does it hurt? - I can't breathe.
不会吧
Oh, no.
你先憋气，好吗？
Hey, hold your breath, okay?
汤姆和妮奇呢？
Where's Tom and Nikki?
在你小时候
You know, when you were little,
我常像这样扶着你学走路
I used to hold you like this to help you walk
我会说“左、右、左”
and I'd say, "Left, right, left."
- 左，对，一起说  - 左、右、左
- Left, yeah, say it with me. - Left, right, left.
我就在你后面
I'm right behind you.
左、右…
Left, right...
爸，你还好吗？
Daddy! Are you okay?
我休息一下，去找妈妈，好吗？
I'm just gonna rest. Go find Mommy, okay?
- 可是爸…  - 继续走
- But, Daddy... - Just keep walking.
不
No.
左、右、左
Left, right, left.
- 继续走  - 左
- Keep going. - Left.
- 我就在你后面  - 左、右、左
- I'm right behind you. - Left, right, left.
我爱你
I love you.
左、右、左…
Left, right, left.
又来了
Here we go again.
我的老天！
Holy moly!
更多太空船！
More spaceships, people!
我们必须靠近那些太空船
We need to get very close to those ships.
好！
Yes!
左、右、左
Left, right, left.
左、右…
Left, right.
宝贝
Honey...
爸爸呢？
Where's Daddy?
他就在我后面
He was right behind me.
汤姆？
Tom!
你最后见到你爸是什么时候？
Hey, when was the last time you saw your daddy?
我不知道
I don't know.
汤姆！
Tom!
又有氧气了
Oxygen's coming back.
- 不，我去找他  - 让开！
- No, no. I'll go look for him. - Get out of the way.
- 你必须留在这儿 - 不，桑尼！
- You have to stay here. - No, Sonny!
- 太危险了  - 你必须照顾他们
- It's too dangerous. - You have to take care of them,
好吗？
okay?
进去隧道里
Go deeper into the tunnel.
妈，你要相信我
You have to trust me, Mom.
桑尼，小心！
Sonny, look out.
桑尼！
Sonny!
我去找他
I'm gonna go find him.
请你帮我照顾吉米
Take care of Jimmy for me, please.
桑尼！
Sonny!
快进去
Come on, guys.
月球从北大西洋进入大气层了
The Moon's entered the atmosphere over the North Atlantic.
将军，倒数二十秒
General, T-minus 20.
倒数三秒
On three.
三、二、一
Three, two, one.
道格，你这是干嘛？
Doug, what the hell are you doing?
我前妻在外太空
My ex-wife is up there.
我老婆在地球，我想救她
Well, my wife's down here, and I'm trying to save her.
把钥匙插回控制器
Put your damn key back in the console.
我不知道为什么
I don't know how,
但我相信她能救我们
but I believe that she can save us.
把钥匙给我！
Give me the damn key.
你要干嘛？把枪放下
What the hell are you doing? Put that gun down.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
桑尼！
Sonny!
布莱恩，我们为何慢下来？
Brian, why are we slowing down?
它在我们后面吗？
Is it behind us?
我没看到它
I don't see it.
乔，你来驾驶
Jo, I need you to take over
我去准备电磁脉冲弹
while I get the EMP ready.
我带着炸弹留在登月车上面
I'm staying behind in the rover with the bomb.
你和KC开着登月舱离开这里
You and KC take the lander and get out of here.
这就是你的计划？
This was your plan?
用你自己当饵？
To use yourself as bait?
我们得有人留下，否则行不通
One of us has to stay in there, or it won't work.
不
No.
- 不，布莱恩  - KC，我需要你去后面
No, no, no, Brian. KC, I need you to go back there,
如果那玩意儿出现了就告诉我
and you let me know if this thing shows up.
快去
Come on.
布莱恩，我是NASA局长
Brian, I'm the director of NASA.
决定权在我，不是你
This is my call, not yours.
对，我是这次任务的指挥官
Yeah, I'm the commander of this mission,
我要留下来
and I'm staying behind.
- 一定有别的办法  - 没别的办法了
- There's gotta be another way. - No, there's no other way, Jo.
你心知肚明，我们一定要解决它
You know that. We have to finish this,
不然我们都死定了
or that thing's gonna finish us.
你有什么毛病？
What's the matter with you?
你把全世界的命运交到前妻手上
You're putting the fate of the world in the hands of your ex-wife,
还有一个过气的宇航员
and some has-been astronaut.
她从来没让我失望
She's never let me down before.
但愿上帝保佑你没错
God help you if you're wrong.
上帝保佑我们大家
God help us all.
桑尼！
Sonny.
桑尼，醒一醒
Sonny, wake up!
不…
No, no.
你不应该回来的
No, you shouldn't have come back.
不能随便丢下别人，懂吗？
You don't leave people behind, okay?
布莱恩，你不能这么做
Brian, you are not gonna do this.
（后舱门开启）
K·C！
KC!
你来接手
Take over.
K·C
KC.
你要干嘛？不！
What are you doing? No.
不！你要干嘛？
No. What are you doing?
我妈常说事先征得许可
My mum always said it's better to beg for forgiveness
不如事后求得原谅
than ask permission.
不，把门打开
No, you open this door.
开门！
Open the door!
大家都当我是个笑话
Everybody thought I was a joke,
只有你肯听我说话…
but you listened to me...
而其他人都不理我
when no one else would.
帮我一个忙
Do something for me.
去看看我妈
Check in on my mum.
跟她说她儿子不是失败者
Tell her that her son wasn't a failure.
不，我不容许你这么做
No. I am not letting you do this.
- 快点  - 布莱恩
- Come on. - Brian,
你没害死那个宇航员
you didn't kill that astronaut.
你救了福勒局长
You saved Director Fowler.
现在也不是你害死我
And you're not killing me now.
你是在拯救全世界
You're saving everyone else.
世界需要你，布莱恩
The world needs you, Brian.
你是解读月球知识的关键
You're the key to our Moon's knowledge.
谢谢你相信我的疯理论
Thanks for believing my crazy stories.
你不疯
You're not crazy.
两位，有件事我必须坦承
Guys, there's something I need to get off my chest.
我不是真正的博士
I'm not a real doctor.
只是写在名片上显得比较酷
I just put that on my business cards 'cause it sounded cool.
去拯救世界吧…
Go save the world,
豪斯曼博士
Dr. Houseman.
你太小看我们了
You underestimated us.
赶快逃！
Get out of here.
桑尼，月球会帮我们的
Sonny, the Moon is going to help us.
快！再试一次！
Come on, try again!
它来了！趁现在！
Here it comes. Now!
要来了！
We have incoming!
撑住，布莱恩
Come on, Bri.
我带你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
桑尼！
Sonny.
桑尼？
谢谢你帮我把他带回来
Thank you for bringing him back to me.
妈？是你吗？
Mom? Is that you?
对，他们都在
Yeah. They're here.
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
克莱斯勒大楼不是在纽约吗？
Isn't the Chrysler Building in New York?
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我错过了什么？
What'd I miss?
孩子们都没事
Well, the kids are okay.
至于地球…
And Earth,
意外地没被摧毁
surprisingly, it's still in one piece.
如果地球能有再一次机会…
You know, if Earth gets a second chance,
我想我们也值得拥有
I think we deserve one, too.
我也想要
I'd like that.
那是追踪装置吗？
Is that a tracking device?
希望是
I sure hope so.
我们合作无间，对吧？
We make a pretty good team, huh?
是啊
Yeah,
没错
we do.
吉米！
Jimmy!
爸！
Dad!
我们没能去找爸爸
We never made it to Dad.
没关系
That's okay.
汤姆呢？
Where's Tom?
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
没有他，我们就到不了这里
We wouldn't have made it here without him.
你朋友呢？
Where's your friend?
他…
He, uh...
他拯救了这个世界
He saved the world.
还有那个世界
And that one, too.
有人吗？
Hello?
毛德林
Fuzz Aldrin.
你做得很好
You did well.
妈…
Mum.
这是什么？
What is this?
我还活着吗？
Am I still alive?
我们扫描了你的意识
We scanned your consciousness.
你现在是月球的一部分了
You're part of the Moon now.
不会吧
No freakin' way.
所以…
So...
我们拯救了地球
We saved the Earth.
我们该开始了
We should get started.
开始什么？
Get started with what?